about_Objects
TOPIC
    about_Objects

SHORT DESCRIPTION
    Provides essential information about objects in Windows PowerShell. 


LONG DESCRIPTION
    Every action you take in Windows PowerShell occurs within the context of
    objects. As data moves from one command to the next, it moves as one or 
    more identifiable objects. An object, then, is a collection of data that 
    represents an item. An object is made up of three types of data: the 
    objects type, its methods, and its properties.


 TYPES, PROPERTIES, AND METHODS

    The object type tells what kind of object it is. For example, an object
    that represents a file is a FileInfo object.

    The object methods are actions that you can perform on the object. 
    For example, FileInfo objects have a CopyTo method that you can use
    to copy the file. 

    Object properties store information about the object. For example,  
    FileInfo objects have a LastWriteTime property that stores the date
    and time that the file was most recently accessed.

    When working with objects, you can use their properties and methods
    in commands to take action and manage data. 


 OBJECTS IN PIPELINES 

    When commands are combined in a pipeline, they pass information to each 
    other as objects. When the first command runs, it sends one or more 
    objects down the pipeline to the second command. The second command 
    receives the objects from the first command, processes the objects, and 
    then passes new or revised objects to the next command in the pipeline. 
    This continues until all commands in the pipeline run.

    The following example demonstrates how objects are passed from one 
    command to the next:

        Get-ChildItem C: | where {$_.PsIsContainer -eq $False} | 
        Format-List


    The first command (Get-ChildItem C:) returns a file or directory
    object for each item in the root directory of the file system. The
    file and directory objects are passed down the pipeline to the second
    command. 

    The second command  (where {$_.PsIsContainer -eq $false}) uses the 
    PsIsContainer property of all file system objects to select only 
    files, which have a value of False ($false) in their PsIsContainer 
    property. Folders, which are containers and, thus, have a value of 
    True ($true) in their PsIsContainer property, are not selected.

    The second command passes only the file objects to the third command
    (Format-List), which displays the file objects in a list.

 FOR MORE INFORMATION
    Now that you understand a bit about objects, see the about_Methods
    help topic to learn how to find and use object methods, the 
    about_Properties topic to learn how to find and use object properties,
    and the Get-Member topic, to learn how to find an object type.


SEE ALSO
    about_Methods
    about_Object_Creation
    about_Properties
    about_Pipelines
    Get-Member













