TOPIC
    about_EventLogs

SHORT DESCRIPTION
    Windows PowerShell creates a Windows event log that is 
    named "Windows PowerShell" to record Windows PowerShell events. You can
    view this log in Event Viewer or by using cmdlets that get events, such as
    the Get-EventLog cmdlet. By default, Windows PowerShell engine and provider
    events are recorded in the event log, but you can use the event log 
    preference variables to customize the event log. For example, you can add
    events about Windows PowerShell commands.


LONG DESCRIPTION
    The Windows PowerShell event log records details of Windows PowerShell 
    operations, such as starting and stopping the program engine and starting
    and stopping the Windows PowerShell providers. You can also log details 
    about Windows PowerShell commands.


    The Windows PowerShell event log is in the Application and Services Logs
    group. The Windows PowerShell log is a classic event log that does not use
    the Windows Eventing technology. To view the log, use the cmdlets designed
    for classic event logs, such as Get-EventLog.


  Viewing the Windows PowerShell Event Log

      You can view the Windows PowerShell event log in Event Viewer or by 
      using the Get-EventLog and Get-WmiObject cmdlets. To view the contents 
      of the Windows PowerShell log, type:

  Get-EventLog -LogName "Windows PowerShell"

   
      To examine the events and their properties, use the Sort-Object cmdlet,
      the Group-Object cmdlet, and the cmdlets that contain the Format verb 
      (the Format cmdlets).


      For example, to view the events in the log grouped by the event ID, type:

  Get-EventLog "Windows PowerShell" | Format-Table -GroupBy EventID


      Or, type:

  Get-EventLog "Windows PowerShell" | Sort-Object EventID `
            | Group-Object EventID


      To view all the classic event logs, type:

  Get-EventLog -List

    
      You can also use the Get-WmiObject cmdlet to use the event-related 
      Windows Management Instumentation (WMI) classes to examine the event log.
      For example, to view all the properties of the event log file, type:

  Get-WmiObject Win32_NTEventLogFile | where `
            {$_.LogFileName -eq "Windows PowerShell"} | Format-List -Property * 


      To find the Win32 event-related WMI classes, type:

Get-WmiObject -List | where {$_.Name -like "win32*event*"}


      For more information, type "Get-Help Get-EventLog" and 
      "Get-Help Get-WmiObject".


  Selecting Events for the Windows PowerShell Event Log

      You can use the event log preference variables to determine which events
      are recorded in the Windows PowerShell event log. 


      There are six event log preference variables; two variables for each of 
      the three logging components: the engine (the Windows PowerShell 
      program), the providers, and the commands. The LifeCycleEvent variables
      log normal starting and stopping events. The Health variables log error
      events.


      The following table lists the event log preference variables.

          Variable                     Description
          --------------------------   ----------------------------------------

  $LogEngineLifeCycleEvent     Logs starting and stopping of
                                       Windows PowerShell.

  $LogEngineHealthEvent        Logs Windows PowerShell program errors.

  $LogProviderLifeCycleEvent   Logs starting and stopping of 
                                       Windows PowerShell providers.

  $LogProviderHealthEvent      Logs Windows PowerShell provider errors.

  $LogCommandLifeCycleEvent    Logs starting and completion of commands.

  $LogCommandHealthEvent       Logs command errors.


      (For information about Windows PowerShell providers, 
      type: "Get-Help about_providers".)


      By default, only the following event types are enabled:

  $LogEngineLifeCycleEvent
  $LogEngineHealthEvent
  $LogProviderLifeCycleEvent
  $LogProviderHealthEvent


      To enable an event type, set the preference variable for that event type
      to $true. For example, to enable command life-cycle events, type:

  $LogCommandLifeCycleEvent


      Or, type:

  $LogCommandLifeCycleEvent = $true


      To disable an event type, set the preference variable for that event type
      to $false. For example, to disable command life-cycle events, type:

  $LogProviderLifeCycleEvent = $false

      You can disable any event, except for the events that indicate that the
      Windows PowerShell engine and the core providers are started. These events
      are generated before the Windows PowerShell profiles are run and before 
      the host program is ready to accept commands.
    
      The variable settings apply only for the current Windows PowerShell 
      session. To apply them to all Windows PowerShell sessions, add them to
      your Windows PowerShell profile.


  Logging Module Events

    Beginning in Windows PowerShell 3.0, you can record execution events for the cmdlets
    and functions in Windows PowerShell modules and snap-ins by setting the
    LogPipelineExecutionDetails property of modules and snap-ins to TRUE. In Windows 
    PowerShell 2.0, this feature is available only for snap-ins.

    When the LogPipelineExecutionDetails property value is TRUE ($True), Windows PowerShell 
    writes cmdlet and function execution events in the session to the Windows PowerShell
    log in Event Viewer. The setting is effective only in the current session.

    To enable logging of execution events of cmdlets and functions in a module, use the
    following command sequence.
        Import-Module <ModuleName>
        $m = Get-Module <ModuleName>
        $m.LogPipelineExecutionDetails = $True

    To enable logging of execution events of cmdlets in a snap-in, use the following
    command sequence.
        $m = Get-PSSnapin <SnapInName> [-Registered]
        $m.LogPipelineExecutionDetails = $True

    To disable logging, use the same command sequence to set the property
    value to FALSE ($False).

    You can also use the "Turn on Module Logging" Group Policy setting to enable
    and disable module and snap-in logging. The policy value includes a list of 
    module and snap-in names. Wildcards are supported.

    When "Turn on Module Logging" is set for a module, the value of the 
    LogPipelineExecutionDetails property of the module is TRUE in all sessions 
    and it cannot be changed.

    The Turn On Module Logging group policy setting is located in the following
    Group Policy paths:

        Computer Configuration\Administrative Templates\Windows Components\Windows PowerShell
        User Configuration\Administrative Templates\Windows Components\Windows PowerShell

    The User Configuration policy takes precedence over the Computer Configuration policy,
    and both policies take preference over the value of the LogPipelineExecutionDetails 
    property of modules and snap-ins.

    For more information about this Group Policy setting, see about_Group_Policy_Settings
    (http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkID=251696).


  Security and Auditing

      The Windows PowerShell event log is designed to indicate activity and 
      to provide operational details for troubleshooting. 


      However, like most Windows-based application event logs, the 
      Windows PowerShell event log is not designed to be secure. It should not
      be used to audit security or to record confidential or proprietary 
      information.


      Event logs are designed to be read and understood by users. Users can 
      read from and write to the log. A malicious user could read an event log
      on a local or remote computer, record false data, and then prevent the
      logging of their activities.


NOTES
    Authors of module authors can add logging features to
    their modules. For more information, see "Writing a Windows PowerShell Module" in
    MSDN at http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkID=144916.


SEE ALSO
    Get-EventLog
    Get-WmiObject
    about_Group_Policy_Settings
    about_Preference_Variables












