TOPIC
    about_Return

SHORT DESCRIPTION
    Exits the current scope, which can be a function, script, or script block.


LONG DESCRIPTION
    The Return keyword exits a function, script, or script block. It can be 
    used to exit a scope at a specific point, to return a value, or to indicate 
    that the end of the scope has been reached. 


    Users who are familiar with languages like C or C# might want to use the 
    Return keyword to make the logic of leaving a scope explicit.
 

    In Windows PowerShell, the results of each statement are returned as 
    output, even without a statement that contains the Return keyword. 
    Languages like C or C# return only the value or values that are specified 
    by the Return keyword. 


  Syntax

      The syntax for the Return keyword is as follows:

          return [<expression>]


      The Return keyword can appear alone, or it can be followed by a value or 
      expression, as follows:

          return
          return $a
          return (2 + $a)


  Examples

      The following example uses the Return keyword to exit a function at a 
      specific point if a conditional is met:

          function ScreenPassword($instance)
          {
              if (!($instance.screensaversecure)) {return $instance.name} 
              <additional statements>
          }

          foreach ($a in @(get-wmiobject win32_desktop)) { ScreenPassword($a) }


      This script checks each user account. The ScreenPassword function returns 
      the name of any user account that does not have a password-protected 
      screen saver. If the screen saver is password protected, the function 
      completes any other statements to be run, and Windows PowerShell does not 
      return any value.


      In Windows PowerShell, values can be returned even if the Return keyword 
      is not used. The results of each statement are returned. For example, the 
      following statements return the value of the $a variable:

          $a
          return


      The following statement also returns the value of $a:

          return $a


      The following example includes a statement intended to let the user know 
      that the function is performing a calculation:

          function calculation {
              param ($value)

              "Please wait. Working on calculation..."
              $value += 73
              return $value
              }


      Running this function and assigning the result to a variable has the 
      following effect:

          C:\PS> $a = calculation 14
          C:\PS>


      The "Please wait. Working on calculation..." string is not displayed. 
      Instead, it is assigned to the $a variable, as in the following example:

          C:\PS> $a
          Please wait. Working on calculation...
          87


      Both the informational string and the result of the calculation are 
      returned by the function and assigned to the $a variable.


SEE ALSO
    about_Functions
    about_Scopes
    about_Script_Blocks















