TOPIC
    about_Line_Editing

SHORT DESCRIPTION
    Describes how to edit commands at the Windows PowerShell command prompt.


LONG DESCRIPTION
    The Windows PowerShell console has some useful features to help
    you to edit commands at the Windows PowerShell command prompt.    

    
    Move Left and Right
        To move the cursor one character to the left, press the LEFT ARROW 
        key. To move the cursor one word to the left, press CTRL+LEFT ARROW.
        To move the cursor one character to the right, press the RIGHT ARROW
        key. To move the cursor one word to the right, press CTRL+RIGHT ARROW. 


    Line Start and End
        To move to the beginning of a line, press the HOME key. To move to the
        end of a line, press the END key. 


    Delete Characters
        To delete the character in behind the cursor, press the BACKSPACE key.
        To delete the character in front of the cursor, press the DELETE key.


    Delete the Remainder of a Line
        To delete all the characters in the line after the cursor, press 
        CTRL+END.


    Insert/Overstrike Mode
        To change to overstrike mode, press the INSERT key. To return to insert
        mode, press INSERT again.


    Tab Completion
        To complete a command, such as the name of a cmdlet, a cmdlet 
        parameter, or a path, press the TAB key. If the first suggestion that
        is displayed is not what you want, press the TAB key again.
 

SEE ALSO
    about_Command_Syntax
    about_Path_Syntax














