TOPIC
    about_Command_Syntax

SHORT DESCRIPTION
    Describes the syntax diagrams that are used in Windows PowerShell.


LONG DESCRIPTION
    The Get-Help and Get-Command cmdlets display syntax diagrams to help
    you construct commands correctly. This topic explains how to interpret
    the syntax diagrams.


  Syntax Diagrams
    Each paragraph in a command syntax diagram represents a valid form
    of the command. 

    To construct a command, follow the syntax diagram from left to
    right. Select from among the optional parameters and provide values for
    the placeholders.

    Windows PowerShell uses the following notation for syntax diagrams.

       <command-name> -<Required Parameter Name> <Required Parameter Value>
                      [-<Optional Parameter Name> <Optional Parameter Value>] 
                      [-<Optional Switch Parameters>] 
                      [-<Optional Parameter Name>] <Required Parameter Value> 


    The following is the syntax for the New-Alias cmdlet.

        New-Alias [-Name] <string> [-Value] <string> [-Description <string>]
            [-Force] [-Option {None | ReadOnly | Constant | Private | AllScope}]
            [-PassThru] [-Scope <string>] [-Confirm] [-WhatIf] [<CommonParameters>]


    The syntax is capitalized for readability, but Windows PowerShell is 
    case-insensitive. 


  The syntax diagram has the following elements.

  Command name
  ------------
    Commands always begin with a command name, such as New-Alias. Type the
    command name or its alias, such a "gcm" for Get-Command. 


  Parameters
  ----------
    The parameters of a command are options that determine what the command
    does. Some parameters take a "value," which is user input to the command.

    For example, the Get-Help command has a Name parameter that lets you
    specify the name of the topic for which help is displayed. The topic
    name is the value of the Name parameter. 

    In a Windows PowerShell command, parameter names always begin with a 
    hyphen. The hyphen tells Windows PowerShell that the item in the command
    is a parameter name.

    For example, to use the Name parameter of New-Alias, you type the following:

        -Name

    Parameters can be mandatory or optional. In a syntax diagram, optional
    items are enclosed in brackets ([ ]).

    For more information about parameters, see about_Parameters.
          
    
  Parameter Values
  ----------------
    A parameter value is the input that the parameter takes. Because Windows
    PowerShell is based on the Microsoft .NET Framework, parameter values are
    represented in the syntax diagram by their .NET type. 

    For example, the Name parameter of Get-Help takes a String value, which
    is a text string, such as a single word or multiple words enclosed in
    quotation marks. 

        [-Name] <string>

    The .NET type of a parameter value is enclosed in angle brackets (< >)
    to indicate that it is placeholder for a value and not a literal 
    that you type in a command.

    To use the parameter, replace the .NET type placeholder with an object
    that has the specified .NET type.
    
    For example, to use the Name parameter, type "-Name" followed by a string,
    such as the following:

        -Name MyAlias

  Parameters with no values
  -------------------------
    Some parameters do not accept input, so they do not have a parameter
    value. Parameters without values are called "switch parameters" 
    because they work like on/off switches. You include them (on) or you
    omit them (off) from a command.
   
    To use a switch parameter, just type the parameter name, preceded by a hyphen.

    For example, to use the WhatIf parameter of the New-Alias cmdlet, type the following:

        -WhatIf

  Parameter Sets
  --------------
    The parameters of a command are listed in parameter sets. Parameter sets
    look like the paragraphs of a syntax diagram.

    The New-Alias cmdlet has one parameter set, but many cmdlets have multiple
    parameter sets. Some of the cmdlet parameters are unique to a parameter set,
    and others appear in multiple parameter sets.

    Each parameter set represents the format of a valid command. A parameter
    set includes only parameters that can be used together in a command. If
    parameters cannot be used in the same command, they appear in separate
    parameter sets.

    For example, the Get-Random cmdlet has the following parameter sets:

        Get-Random [[-Maximum] <Object>] [-Minimum <Object>] [-SetSeed <int>]
                    [<CommonParameters>]

        Get-Random [-InputObject] <Object[]> [-Count <int>] [-SetSeed <int>]
                   [<CommonParameters>]

    The first parameter set, which returns a random number, has the Minimum
    and Maximum parameters. The second parameter set, which returns a randomly
    selected object from a set of objects, includes the InputObject and Count
    parameters. Both parameter sets have the Set-Seed parameter and the common
    parameters.

    These parameter sets indicate that you can use the InputObject and Count
    parameters in the same command, but you cannot use the Maximum and Count
    parameters in the same command.

    You indicate which parameter set you want to use by using the parameters
    in that parameter set. 

    However, every cmdlet also has a default parameter set. The default parameter
    set is used when you do not specify parameters that are unique to a parameter 
    set. For example, if you use Get-Random without parameters, Windows PowerShell
    assumes that you are using the Number parameter set and it returns a random number.

    In each parameter set, the parameters appear in position order. The order of
    parameters in a command matters only when you omit the optional parameter names.
    When parameter names are omitted, Windows PowerShell assigns values to
    parameters by position and type. For more information about parameter position, 
    see about_Parameters.


  Symbols in Syntax Diagrams
    The syntax diagram lists the command name, the command parameters, and the 
    parameter values. It also uses symbols to show how to construct a valid
    command.
    
    The syntax diagrams use the following symbols:


    -- A hyphen (-) indicates a parameter name. In a command, type the hyphen
       immediately before the parameter name with no intervening spaces, as
       shown in the syntax diagram.

       For example, to use the Name parameter of New-Alias, type:

           -Name 

    -- Angle brackets (<>) indicate placeholder text. You do not type the
       angle brackets or the placeholder text in a command. Instead, you replace
       it with the item that it describes. 

       Angle brackets are used to identify the .NET type of the value that
       a parameter takes. For example, to use the Name parameter of the New-Alias
       cmdlet, you replace the <string> with a string, which is a single word or a
       group of words that are enclosed in quotation marks.
      
        
    -- Brackets ([ ]) indicate optional items. A parameter and its value can be
       optional, or the name of a required parameter can be optional. 
 
       For example, the Description parameter of New-Alias and its value are
       enclosed in brackets because they are both optional. 
 
   [-Description <string>]
       
       
       The brackets also indicate that the Name parameter value (<string>) is
       required, but the parameter name, "Name," is optional. 

         [-Name] <string>


    -- A right and left bracket ([]) appended to a .NET type indicates that
       the parameter can accept one or multiple values of that type. Enter the 
       values in a comma-separated list.

       For example, the Name parameter of the New-Alias cmdlet takes only 
       one string, but the Name parameter of Get-Process can take one or 
       many strings.

          New-Alias [-Name] <string>

               New-Alias -Name MyAlias

          Get-Process [-Name] <string[]>

               Get-Process -Name Explorer, Winlogon, Services
               

    -- Braces ({}) indicate an "enumeration," which is a set of valid values
       for a parameter. 
 
       The values in the braces are separated by vertical bars ( | ). These bars       
       indicate an "exclusive or" choice, meaning that you can choose only
       one value from the set of values that are listed inside the braces. 

       For example, the syntax for the New-Alias cmdlet includes the following
       value enumeration for the Option parameter:

          -Option {None | ReadOnly | Constant | Private | AllScope}

       The braces and vertical bars indicate that you can choose any one of
       the listed values for the Option parameter, such as ReadOnly or AllScope.

          -Option ReadOnly



  Optional Items
      Brackets ([]) surround optional items. For example, in the New-Alias 
      cmdlet syntax description, the Scope parameter is optional. This is 
      indicated in the syntax by the brackets around the parameter name 
      and type:

          [-Scope <string>]


      Both the following examples are correct uses of the New-Alias cmdlet:

          New-Alias -Name utd -Value Update-TypeData
          New-Alias -Name utd -Value Update-TypeData -Scope global


      A parameter name can be optional even if the value for that parameter is 
      required. This is indicated in the syntax by the brackets around the 
      parameter name but not the parameter type, as in this example from the 
      New-Alias cmdlet:

          [-Name] <string> [-Value] <string>


      The following  commands correctly use the New-Alias cmdlet. The commands 
      produce the same result.

          New-Alias -Name utd -Value Update-TypeData
          New-Alias -Name utd Update-TypeData
          New-Alias utd -Value Update-TypeData
          New-Alias utd Update-TypeData


      If the parameter name is not included in the statement as typed, Windows 
      PowerShell tries to use the position of the arguments to assign the 
      values to parameters.


      The following example is not complete:

          New-Alias utd


      This cmdlet requires values for both the Name and Value parameters.


      In syntax examples, brackets are also used in naming and casting to 
      .NET Framework types. In this context, brackets do not indicate an 
      element is optional.

KEYWORDS
    about_Symbols
    about_Punctuation
    about_Help_Syntax

SEE ALSO
    about_Parameters
    Get-Command
    Get-Help












