TOPIC
    about_Continue

SHORT DESCRIPTION
    Describes how the Continue statement immediately returns the program flow
    to the top of a program loop.


LONG DESCRIPTION
    In a script, the Continue statement immediately returns the program flow
    to the top of the innermost loop that is controlled by a For, Foreach, or
    While statement.
    
    
    The Continue keyword supports labels. A label is a name you assign to a 
    statement in a script. For information about labels, see about_Break.
    
    
    In the following example, program flow returns to the top of the While loop
    if the $ctr variable is equal to 5. As a result, all the numbers between 1 
    and 10 are displayed except for 5:
    
        while ($ctr -lt 10)
             {
               $ctr +=1 
               if ($ctr -eq 5) {continue}
               Write-Host $ctr
             }
    
    
    Note that in a For loop, execution continues at the first line in the 
    loop. If the arguments of the For statement test a value that is 
    modified by the For statement, an infinite loop may result.

    
SEE ALSO
    about_Break
    about_Comparison_Operators
    about_Throw
    about_Trap
    about_Try_Catch_Finally













