TOPIC
	TestDrive

SYNOPSIS
	A PSDrive for file activity limited to the scope of a singe Describe or 
	Context block.

DESCRIPTION	
	A test may need to work with file operations and validate certain tyes of 
	file activities. It is usually desirable not to perform file activity tests 
	that will produce side effects outside of an individual test. Pester 
	creates a PSDrive inside the user's temporary drive that is accesible via a 
	names PSDrive TestDrive:. Pester will remove this drive after the test 
	completes. You may use this drive to isolate the file operations of your 
	test to a temporary store.

EXAMPLE
	function Add-Footer($path, $footer) {
	    Add-Content $path -Value $footer
	}

	Describe "Add-Footer" {
	    $testPath="TestDrive:\test.txt"
	    Set-Content $testPath -value "my test text."
	    Add-Footer $testPath "-Footer"
	    $result = Get-Content $testPath

	    It "adds a footer" {
	        (-join $result).Should.Be("my test text.-Footer")
	    }
	}
	
	When this test completes, the contents of the TestDrive PSDrive will 
	be removed.

SEE ALSO
	Context
	Describe
	It
	about_Should

