TOPIC
    about_PowerShell_Ise.exe

SHORT DESCRIPTION
    Explains how to use the PowerShell_Ise.exe command-line tool. 
    Displays the syntax and describes the command-line switches.

    PowerShell_Ise.exe starts a Windows PowerShell Integrated
    Scripting Environment (ISE) session. You can run it in Cmd.exe
    and in Windows PowerShell. 

    To run PowerShell_ISE.exe, type PowerShell_ISE.exe, PowerShell_ISE, 
    or ISE.

LONG DESCRIPTION
 SYNTAX
     PowerShell_Ise[.exe]
     PowerShell_ISE[.exe]
     ISE[.exe]
          [–File]<FilePath[]> [–NoProfile] [–MTA]
          –Help | ? | -? | /? 

 PARAMETERS
    -File
    Opens the specified files in Windows PowerShell ISE. The 
    parameter name ("-File") is optional. To list more than one 
    file, enter one text string enclosed in quotation marks. Use 
    commas to separate the file names within the string. 

    For example:
        PowerShell_ISE -File "File1.ps1,File2.ps1,File3.xml". 

    Spaces between the file names are permitted in Windows PowerShell, 
    but might not be interpreted correctly by other programs, such as 
    Cmd.exe.

    You can use this parameter to open any text file, including Windows 
    PowerShell script files and XML files.


    -Mta
    Starts Windows PowerShell ISE using a multi-threaded apartment. This 
    parameter is introduced in Windows PowerShell 3.0. Single-threaded 
    apartment (STA) is the default.

    -NoProfile
    Does not run Windows PowerShell profiles. By default, Windows PowerShell 
    profiles are run in every session.

    This parameter is recommended when you are writing shared content, such as 
    functions and scripts that will be run on systems with different profiles. 
    For more information, see about_Profiles 
    (http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkID=113729).

    -Help, -?, /?
    Displays help for PowerShell_ISE.exe.

 EXAMPLES
    These commands start Windows PowerShell ISE. The commands are equivalent
    and can be used interchangeably.

        PS C:\>PowerShell_ISE.exe
        PS C:\>PowerShell_ISE
        PS C:\>ISE

    These commands open the Get-Profile.ps1 script in Windows PowerShell ISE. 
    The commands are equivalent and can be used interchangeably.

        PS C:\>PowerShell_ISE.exe -File .\Get-Profile.ps1
        PS C:\>ISE -File .\Get-Profile.ps1
        PS C:\>ISE .\Get-Profile.ps1

    This command opens the Get-Backups.ps1 and Get-BackupInstance.ps1 scripts 
    in Windows PowerShell ISE. To open more than one file, use a comma to 
    separate the file names and enclose the entire file name value in quotation 
    marks.
 
        PS C:\>ISE -File ".\Get-Backups.ps1,Get-BackupInstance.ps1"


    This command starts Windows PowerShell ISE with no profiles.

        PS C:\>ISE -NoProfile

    This command gets help for PowerShell_ISE.exe.

        PS C:\>ISE -help


SEE ALSO
    about_PowerShell.exe
    about_Windows_PowerShell_ISE
    Windows PowerShell 3.0 Integrated Scripting Environment (ISE)













