TOPIC
    about_WS-Management_Cmdlets

SHORT DESCRIPTION
    Provides an overview of Web Services for Management (WS-Management) as 
    background for using the WS-Management cmdlets in Windows PowerShell.

LONG DESCRIPTION
    This topic provides an overview of Web Services for Management 
    (WS-Management) as background for using the WS-Management cmdlets in
    Windows PowerShell. This topic also provides links to more information
    about WS-Management. The Microsoft implementation of WS-Management is also
    known as Windows Remote Management (WinRM).


  About WS-Management 

      Windows Remote Management is the Microsoft implementation
      of the WS-Management protocol, a standard SOAP-based, firewall-friendly 
      protocol that allows hardware and operating systems from different 
      vendors to interoperate. The WS-Management protocol specification 
      provides a common way for systems to access and exchange management 
      information across an information technology (IT) infrastructure.
      WS-Management and Intelligent Platform Management Interface (IPMI),
      along with the Event Collector, are components of the Windows Hardware
      Management features. 

      The WS-Management protocol is based on the following standard Web service
      specifications: HTTPS, SOAP over HTTP (WS-I profile), SOAP 1.2, 
      WS-Addressing, WS-Transfer, WS-Enumeration, and WS-Eventing. 


  WS-Management and WMI

      WS-Management can be used to retrieve data exposed by Windows Management
      Instrumentation (WMI). You can obtain WMI data with scripts or 
      applications that use the WS-Management Scripting API or through the 
      WinRM command-line tool. WS-Management supports most of the familiar WMI
      classes and operations, including embedded objects. WS-Management can 
      leverage WMI to collect data about resources or to manage resources on a
      Windows-based computers. That means that you can obtain data 
      about objects such as disks, network adapters, services, or processes
      in your enterprise through the existing set of WMI classes. You can also
      access the hardware data that is available from the standard WMI IPMI 
      provider.


  WS-Management Windows PowerShell Provider (WSMan)

      The WSMan provider provides a hierarchical view into the 
      available WS-Management configuration settings. The provider allows you
      to explore and set the various WS-Management configuration options. 

                 
  WS-Management Configuration

      If WS-Management is not installed and configured, Windows PowerShell 
      remoting is not available, the WS-Management cmdlets do not run, 
      WS-Management scripts do not run, and the WSMan provider cannot
      perform data operations. The WS-Management command-line tool, WinRM, 
      and event forwarding also depend on the WS-Management configuration.


  WS-Management Cmdlets

      WS-Management functionality is implemented in Windows PowerShell through
      a module that contains a set of cmdlets and the WSMan provider. 
      You can use these cmdlets to complete the end-to-end tasks necessary 
      to manage WS-Management settings on local and remote computers.
 
      The following WS-Management cmdlets are available.

     Connection Cmdlets

     -- Connect-WSMan: Connects the local computer to the WS-Management 
        (WinRM) service on a remote computer.

     -- Disconnect-WSMan: Disconnects the local computer from the WS-Management
        (WinRM) service on a remote computer.

     Management-Data Cmdlets

     -- Get-WSManInstance: Displays management information for a resource 
        instance that is specified by a resource URI.

     -- Invoke-WSManAction: Invokes an action on the target object that 
        is specified by the resource URI and by the selectors.

     -- New-WSManInstance: Creates a new management resource instance.

     -- Remove-WSManInstance: Deletes a management resource instance.

     -- Set-WSManInstance: Modifies the management information that is 
        related to a resource.
 
     Setup and Configuration Cmdlets

     -- Set-WSManQuickConfig: Configures the local computer for remote 
        management. You can use the Set-WSManQuickConfig cmdlet to configure
        WS-Management to allow remote connections to the WS-Management (WinRM)
        service. The Set-WSManQuickConfig cmdlet performs the following 
        operations:

- It determines whether the WS-Management (WinRM) service is running.
          If the WinRM service is not running, the Set-WSManQuickConfig cmdlet
          starts the service.

- It sets the WS-Management (WinRM) service startup type to automatic.

- It creates a listener that accepts requests from any IP address. 
          The default transport protocol is HTTP.

- It enables a firewall exception for WS-Management traffic.

Note: To run this cmdlet in Windows Vista, Windows Server 2008, and
              later versions of Windows, you must start Windows PowerShell 
              with the "Run as administrator" option.

     -- Test-WSMan: Verifies that WS-Management is installed and configured. 
        The Test-WSMan cmdlet tests whether the WS-Management (WinRM) 
        service is running and configured on a local or remote computer.

     -- Disable-WSManCredSSP: Disables CredSSP authentication on a client
        computer.

     -- Enable-WSManCredSSP: Enables CredSSP authentication on a client 
        computer.
 
     -- Get-WSManCredSSP: Gets the CredSSP-related configuration for a 
        client computer.

     WS-Management-Specific Cmdlets

     -- New-WSManSessionOption: Creates a WSManSessionOption object to use as
        input to one or more parameters of a WS-Management cmdlet.

    
  Additional WS-Management Information
   
    For more information about WS-Management, see the following topics in the
    MSDN (Microsoft Developer Network) library.
 
      "Windows Remote Management"
      http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=142321
    
      "About Windows Remote Management"
      http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=142322

      "Installation and Configuration for Windows Remote Management"
      http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=142323

      "Windows Remote Management Architecture"
      http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=142324

      "WS-Management Protocol"
      http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=142325

      "Windows Remote Management and WMI"
      http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=142326

      "Resource URIs"
      http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=142327

      "Remote Hardware Management"
      http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=142328

      "Events"
      http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=142329


SEE ALSO
    Online version: http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=142331 
    Connect-WSMan
    Disable-WSManCredSSP
    Disconnect-WSMan
    Enable-WSManCredSSP
    Get-WSManCredSSP
    Get-WSManInstance
    Invoke-WSManAction
    New-WSManInstance
    Remove-WSManInstance
    Set-WSManInstance
    Set-WSManQuickConfig
    Set-WSManSessionOption 
    Test-WSMan
 
KEYWORDS
    about_WSMAN about_WinRM













