TOPIC
    about_PowerShell.exe

SHORT DESCRIPTION
    Explains how to use the PowerShell.exe command-line tool. Displays
    the syntax and describes the command-line switches.

    PowerShell.exe starts a Windows PowerShell session. You can use it
    in Cmd.exe and in Windows PowerShell. 

LONG DESCRIPTION
 SYNTAX
     PowerShell[.exe]
       [-EncodedCommand <Base64EncodedCommand>]
       [-ExecutionPolicy <ExecutionPolicy>]
       [-InputFormat {Text | XML}] 
       [-Mta]
       [-NoExit]
       [-NoLogo]
       [-NonInteractive] 
       [-NoProfile] 
       [-OutputFormat {Text | XML}] 
       [-PSConsoleFile <FilePath> | -Version <Windows PowerShell version>]
       [-Sta]
       [-WindowStyle <style>]
       [-File <FilePath> [<Args>]]
       [-Command { - | <script-block> [-args <arg-array>]
                     | <string> [<CommandParameters>] } ]
     PowerShell[.exe] -Help | -? | /?

 PARAMETERS

    -EncodedCommand <Base64EncodedCommand>
    Accepts a base-64-encoded string version of a command. 
    Use this parameter to submit commands to Windows PowerShell 
    that require complex quotation marks or curly braces.

    -ExecutionPolicy <ExecutionPolicy>
    Sets the default execution policy for the current session
    and saves it in the $env:PSExecutionPolicyPreference environment
    variable. This parameter does not change the Windows PowerShell 
    execution policy that is set in the registry. For information 
    about Windows PowerShell execution policies, including a list 
    of valid values, see about_Execution_Policies 
    (http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkID=135170).

    -File <FilePath> [<Parameters>]
    Runs the specified script in the local scope ("dot-sourced"), 
    so that the functions and variables that the script creates 
    are available in the current session. Enter the script file 
    path and any parameters. File must be the last parameter in 
    the command, because all characters typed after the File 
    parameter name are interpreted as the script file path followed
    by the script parameters.

    You can include the parameters of a script, and parameter 
    values, in the value of the File parameter. For example: 
    -File .\Get-Script.ps1 -Domain Central

    Typically, the switch parameters of a script are either 
    included or omitted. For example, the following command 
    uses the All parameter of the Get-Script.ps1 script file: 
    -File .\Get-Script.ps1 -All

    In rare cases, you might need to provide a Boolean value 
    for a switch parameter. To provide a Boolean value for a 
    switch parameter in the value of the File parameter, 
    enclose the parameter name and value in curly braces, 
    such as the following: 
    -File .\Get-Script.ps1 {-All:$False}. 


    -InputFormat {Text | XML}
    Describes the format of data sent to Windows PowerShell. Valid
    values are "Text" (text strings) or "XML" (serialized CLIXML format).

    -Mta
    Starts Windows PowerShell using a multi-threaded apartment. This
    parameter is introduced in Windows PowerShell 3.0. In Windows 
    PowerShell 2.0, multi-threaded apartment (MTA) is the default. 
    In Windows PowerShell 3.0, single-threaded apartment (STA) is 
    the default.

    -NoExit
    Does not exit after running startup commands.

    -NoLogo
    Hides the copyright banner at startup.

    -NonInteractive
    Does not present an interactive prompt to the user.

    -NoProfile
    Does not load the Windows PowerShell profile.

    -OutputFormat {Text | XML}
    Determines how output from Windows PowerShell is formatted. 
    Valid values are "Text" (text strings) or "XML" (serialized 
    CLIXML format).

    -PSConsoleFile <FilePath>
    Loads the specified Windows PowerShell console file. Enter 
    the path and name of the console file. To create a console file, 
    use the Export-Console cmdlet in Windows PowerShell.

    -Sta
    Starts Windows PowerShell using a single-threaded apartment. In 
    Windows PowerShell 2.0, multi-threaded apartment (MTA) is the default. 
    In Windows PowerShell 3.0, single-threaded apartment (STA) is the 
    default.

    -Version <Windows PowerShell Version>
    Starts the specified version of Windows PowerShell. Valid values
    are 2.0 and 3.0. The version that you specify must be installed 
    on the system. If Windows PowerShell 3.0 is installed on the 
    computer, "3.0" is the default version. Otherwise, "2.0" is the 
    default version. For more information, see "Installing Windows 
    PowerShell" in the Windows PowerShell Getting Started Guide.

    -WindowStyle <Window style>
    Sets the window style for the session. Valid values are Normal, 
    Minimized, Maximized and Hidden.

    -Command
    Executes the specified commands (and any parameters) as though 
    they were typed at the Windows PowerShell command prompt, and 
    then exits, unless the NoExit parameter is specified. 

    The value of Command can be "-", a string. or a script block. If 
    the value of Command is "-", the command text is read from standard 
    input.

    Script blocks must be enclosed in braces ({}). You can specify a 
    script block only when running PowerShell.exe in Windows PowerShell. 
    The results of the script are returned to the parent shell as 
    deserialized XML objects, not live objects.

    If the value of Command is a string, Command must be the last 
    parameter in the command , because any characters typed after 
    the command are interpreted as the command arguments.

    To write a string that runs a Windows PowerShell command, use the
    format:
         "& {<command>}"
    where the quotation marks indicate a string and the invoke operator
    (&) causes the command to be executed.

    -Help, -?, /?
    Displays help for PowerShell.exe. If you are typing a PowerShell.exe 
    command in Windows PowerShell, prepend the command parameters with a 
    hyphen (-), not a forward slash (/). You can use either a hyphen or 
    forward slash in Cmd.exe.


 REMARKS:  
    Troubleshooting note: In Windows PowerShell 2.0, starting some programs
    from the Windows PowerShell console fails with a LastExitCode of 0xc0000142. 
 


 EXAMPLES
    PowerShell -PSConsoleFile sqlsnapin.psc1

    PowerShell -Version 2.0 -NoLogo -InputFormat text -OutputFormat XML

    PowerShell -Command {Get-EventLog -LogName security}

    PowerShell -Command "& {Get-EventLog -LogName security}"

# To use the -EncodedCommand parameter:
    $command = "dir 'c:\program files' "
    $bytes = [System.Text.Encoding]::Unicode.GetBytes($command)
    $encodedCommand = [Convert]::ToBase64String($bytes)
    powershell.exe -encodedCommand $encodedCommand


 SEE ALSO
    about_PowerShell_Ise.exe (http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkID=256512)













