about_WMI
TOPIC
    about_WMI

SHORT DESCRIPTION
    Windows Management Instrumentation (WMI) uses the 
    Common Information Model (CIM) to represent systems, 
    applications, networks, devices, and other manageable 
    components of the modern enterprise.

LONG DESCRIPTION
    Windows Management Instrumentation (WMI) is 
    Microsoft’s implementation of Web-Based Enterprise 
    Management (WBEM), the industry standard. 

    Classic WMI uses DCOM to communicate with networked
    devices to manage remote systems. Windows PowerShell 
    3.0 introduces a CIM provider model that uses WinRM 
    to remove the dependency on DCOM. This CIM provider 
    model also uses new WMI provider APIs that enable 
    developers to write Windows PowerShell cmdlets in 
    native code (C++). 

    Do not confuse WMI providers with Windows PowerShell
    providers. Many Windows features have an
    associated WMI provider that exposes their management 
    capabilities. To get WMI providers, run a WMI query 
    that gets instances of the __Provider WMI class, such 
    as the following query.

        Get-WmiObject -Class __Provider


THREE COMPONENTS OF WMI

    The following three components of WMI interact with
    Windows PowerShell: Namespaces, Providers, and Classes.

    WMI Namespaces organize WMI providers and WMI classes
    into groups of related components. In this way, they 
    are similar to .NET Framework namespaces. 
    Namespaces are not physical locations, but are more 
    like logical databases. All WMI namespaces are instances
    of the __Namespace system class. The default WMI 
    namespace is Root/CIMV2 (since Microsoft Windows 2000).
    To use Windows PowerShell to get WMI namespaces in the 
    current session, use a command with the following format.

        Get-WmiObject -Class __Namespace

    To get WMI namespaces in other namespaces, use the 
    Namespace parameter to change the location of the search.
    The following command finds WMI namespaces that reside 
    in the Root/Cimv2/Applications namespace.

        Get-WmiObject -Class __Namespace -Namespace 
        root/CIMv2/applications

    WMI namespaces are hierarchical. Therefore, obtaining a
    list of all namespaces on a particular system requires
    performing a recursive query starting at the root 
    namespace.

    WMI Providers expose information about Windows manageable
    objects. A provider retrieves data from a component,
    and passes that data through WMI to a management 
    application, such as Windows PowerShell. Most WMI 
    providers are dynamic providers, which means that they
    obtain the data dynamically when it is requested through
    the management application. 


FINDING WMI CLASSES

    In a default installation of Windows 8, there are more 
    than 1,100 WMI classes in Root/Cimv2. With this many WMI
    classes, the challenge becomes identifying the 
    appropriate WMI class to use to perform a specific task.
    Windows PowerShell 3.0 provides two ways to find WMI 
    classes that are related to a specific topic. 

    For example,to find WMI classes in the root\CIMV2 WMI
    namespace that are related to disks, you can use a
    query such as the one shown here.

        Get-WmiObject -List *disk*

    To find WMI classes that are related to memory, you 
    might use a query such as the one shown here.

        Get-WmiObject -List *memory*

    The CIM cmdlets also provide the ability to discover
    WMI classes. To do this, use the Get-CIMClass cmdlet.
    The command shown here lists WMI classes related 
    to video.

        Get-CimClass *video*

    Tab expansion works when changing WMI namespaces, 
    and therefore use of tab expansion makes sub-WMI 
    namespaces easily discoverable. In the following 
    example, the Get-CimClass cmdlet lists WMI 
    classes related to power settings. To find it, 
    type the root/CIMV2/ WMI namespace, and then press
    the Tab key several times until the
    power namespace appears. Here is the command: 

        Get-CimClass *power* -Namespace root/cimv2/power














