TOPIC
    about_Remote_Disconnected_Session

SHORT DESCRIPTION
    Explains how to disconnect from and reconnect to a PSSession

LONG DESCRIPTION
    Beginning in Windows PowerShell 3.0, you can disconnect from
    a PSSession and reconnect to the PSSession at a later time on
    the same computer or a different computer. The session state
    is maintained and commands in the PSSession continue to
    run while the session is disconnected.

    The Disconnected Sessions feature is available only when the 
    computer at the remote end of a connection is running Windows 
    PowerShell 3.0 or a later version of Windows PowerShell.

    The Disconnected Sessions feature allows you to close the session
    in which a PSSession was created, and even close Windows PowerShell,
    and shut down the computer, without disrupting commands running
    in the PSSession. It is especially useful for running commands that
    take an extended time to complete, and it provides the time and
    device flexibility that IT professionals require.
 
    NOTE: You cannot disconnect from an interactive session that
          is started by using the Enter-PSSession cmdlet.
 
    You can use Disconnected Sessions to manage PSSessions that
    were disconnected unintentionally as the result of a computer
    or network outage.

    In real-world use, the Disconnected Sessions feature allows
    you to begin solving a problem, turn your attention to a higher
    priority issue, and then resume work on the solution, even on a
    different computer in a different location. 


 DISCONNECTED SESSION CMDLETS
    The following cmdlets support the Disconnected Sessions
    feature:

        Disconnect-PSSession:  Disconnects a PSSession.

        Connect-PSSession:     Connects to a disconnected PSSession.

        Receive-PSSession:     Gets the results of commands that ran
                               in disconnected sessions.

        Get-PSSession:         Gets PSSessions on the local computer or
                               on remote computers.

        Invoke-Command:        InDisconnectedSession parameter creates
                               a PSSession and disconnects immediately.



 HOW THE DISCONNECTED SESSIONS FEATURE WORKS
    Beginning in Windows PowerShell 3.0, PSSessions are independent
    of the sessions in which they are created. Active PSSession are
    maintained on the remote computer or "server side" of the 
    connection, even if the session in which PSSession was
    created is closed and the originating computer is shut down
    or disconnected from the network. 

    In Windows PowerShell 2.0, the PSSession is deleted from the 
    remote computer when it is disconnected from the originating
    session or the session in which it was created ends.

    When you disconnect a PSSession, the PSSession remains active
    and is maintained on the remote computer. The session state
    changes from Running to Disconnected. You can reconnect to a
    disconnected PSSession from the current session or from a different
    session on the same computer, or from a different computer. The
    remote computer that maintains the session must be running and 
    be connected to the network.

    Commands in a disconnected PSSession continue to run
    uninterrupted on the remote computer until the command 
    completes or the output buffer fills. To prevent a full
    output buffer from suspending a command, use the 
    OutputBufferingMode parameter of the Disconnect-PSSession,
    New-PSSessionOption, or New-PSTransportOption cmdlets.

    Disconnected sessions are maintained in the disconnected 
    state on the remote computer. They are available for you to 
    reconnect, until you delete the PSSession, such as by using
    the Remove-PSSession cmdlet, or until the idle timeout of the
    PSSession expires. You can adjust the idle timeout of a PSSession
    by using the IdleTimeoutSec or IdleTimeout parameters of the
    Disconnect-PSSession, New-PSSessionOption, or New-PSTransportOption
    cmdlets.

    Another user can connect to PSSessions that you created, 
    but only if they can supply the credentials that were used 
    to create the session, or use the RunAs credentials of
    the session configuration.


  HOW TO GET PSSESSIONS
    Beginning in Windows PowerShell 3.0, the Get-PSSession cmdlet gets
    PSSessions on the local computer and remote computers. It can also
    get PSSessions that were created in the current session.

    To get PSsessions on the local computer or remote computers, use the
    ComputerName or ConnectionUri parameters. Without parameters, 
    Get-PSSession gets PSSession that were created in the local session, 
    regardless of where they terminate.

    When getting PSSessions, remember to look for them on the computer
    on which they are maintained, that is, the remote or "server-side"
    computer.

    For example, if you create a PSSession to the Server01 computer, 
    get the session from the Server01 computer. If you create a PSSession
    from another computer to the local computer, get the session from
    the local computer.
    
    The following command sequence shows how Get-PSSession works.    

    The first command creates a session to the Server01 computer. The
    session resides on the Server01 computer.    

      PS C:\ps-test> New-PSSession -ComputerName Server01

      Id Name            ComputerName    State         ConfigurationName     Availability
      -- ----            ------------    -----         -----------------     ------------
       2 Session2        Server01        Opened        Microsoft.PowerShell     Available

    
    To get the session, use the ComputerName parameter of Get-PSSession
    with a value of Server01.

      PS C:\ps-test> Get-PSSession -ComputerName Server01

      Id Name            ComputerName    State         ConfigurationName     Availability
      -- ----            ------------    -----         -----------------     ------------
       2 Session2        Server01        Opened        Microsoft.PowerShell     Available


    If the value of the ComputerName parameter of Get-PSSession is 
    localhost, Get-PSSession gets PSSessions that terminate at and are
    maintained on the local computer. It does not get PSSessions on the 
    Server01 computer, even if they were started on the local computer.


      PS C:\ps-test> Get-PSSession -ComputerName localhost
      PS C:\ps-test> 


    To get sessions that were created in the current session, use the
    Get-PSSession cmdlet without parameters. This command gets the PSSession
    that was created in the current session and connects to the Server01 computer.

      PS C:\ps-test> Get-PSSession

      Id Name            ComputerName    State         ConfigurationName     Availability
      -- ----            ------------    -----         -----------------     ------------
       2 Session2        Server01        Opened        Microsoft.PowerShell     Available



 HOW TO DISCONNECT SESSIONS
   To disconnect a PSSession use the Disconnect-PSSession cmdlet. To 
   identify the PSSession, use the Session parameter, or pipe a PSSession
   from the New-PSSession or Get-PSSession cmdlets to Disconnect-PSSession.

   The following command disconnects the PSSession to the Server01 computer.
   Notice that the value of the State property is Disconnected and the
   Availability is None.


     PS C:\> Get-PSSession -ComputerName Server01 | Disconnect-PSSession

     Id Name            ComputerName    State         ConfigurationName     Availability
     -- ----            ------------    -----         -----------------     ------------
      2 Session2        Server01        Disconnected  Microsoft.PowerShell          None



   To create a disconnected session, use the InDisconnectedSession parameter
   of the Invoke-Command cmdlet. It creates a session, starts the command, 
   and disconnects immediately, before the command can return any output.
 
   The following command runs a Get-WinEvent command in a disconnected 
   session on the Server02 remote computer.


     PS C:\> Invoke-Command -ComputerName Server02 -InDisconnectedSession `
             -ScriptBlock {Get-WinEvent -LogName "Windows PowerShell"} 

     Id Name            ComputerName    State         ConfigurationName     Availability
     -- ----            ------------    -----         -----------------     ------------
      4 Session3        Server02        Disconnected  Microsoft.PowerShell          None




  HOW TO CONNECT TO DISCONNECTED SESSIONS
    You can connect to any available disconnected PSSession from the session
    in which you created the PSSession or from other sessions on the local
    computer or other computers.
      
    You can create a PSSession, run commands in the PSSession, disconnect from 
    the PSSession, close Windows PowerShell, and shut down the computer. Hours
    later, you can open a different computer, get the PSSession, connect to it, 
    and get the results of commands that ran in the PSSession while it was
    disconnected. Then you can run more commands in the session.
   
    To connect a disconnected PSSession, use the Connect-PSSession cmdlet. Use
    the ComputerName or ConnectionUri parameters to identify the PSSession, or
    pipe a PSSession from Get-PSSession to Connect-PSSession. 

    The following command gets the sessions on the Server02 computer. The output
    includes two disconnected sessions, both of which are available.


     PS C:\> Get-PSSession -ComputerName Server02

     Id Name            ComputerName    State         ConfigurationName     Availability
     -- ----            ------------    -----         -----------------     ------------
      2 Session2        juneb-srv8320   Disconnected  Microsoft.PowerShell          None
      4 Session3        juneb-srv8320   Disconnected  Microsoft.PowerShell          None



    The following command connects to Session2. The PSSession is now open and available.

     PS C:> Connect-PSSession -ComputerName Server02 -Name Session2


     Id Name            ComputerName    State         ConfigurationName     Availability
     -- ----            ------------    -----         -----------------     ------------
      2 Session2        juneb-srv8320   Opened        Microsoft.PowerShell     Available


     
  HOW TO GET THE RESULTS
    To get the results of commands that ran in a disconnected PSSession, use
    the Receive-PSSession cmdlet. 

    You can use Receive-PSSession in addition to, or instead of, using the
    Connect-PSSession cmdlet. If the session is already reconnected, 
    Receive-PSSession gets the results of commands that ran when the session
    was disconnected. If the PSSession is still disconnected, Receive-PSSession
    connects to it and then gets the results of commands that ran while it was
    disconnected.

    Receive-PSSession can return the results in a job (asynchronously) or to 
    the host program (synchronously). Use the OutTarget parameter to select Job 
    or Host. Host is the default value. However, if the command that is being 
    received was started in the current session as a job, it is returned as a job
    by default. 

    The following command uses the Receive-PSSession cmdlet to connect to the PSSession
    on the Server02 computer and get the results of the Get-WinEvent command that
    ran in the Session3 session. The command uses the OutTarget parameter to get the
    results in a job.

   

      PS C:\> Receive-PSSession  -ComputerName Server02 -Name Session3 -OutTarget Job

      Id     Name            PSJobTypeName   State         HasMoreData     Location
      --     ----            -------------   -----         -----------     --------
      3      Job3            RemoteJob       Running       True            Server02   



    To get the results of the job, use the Receive-Job cmdlet.

      PS C:\ps-test> Get-Job | Receive-Job -Keep


          ProviderName: PowerShell

     TimeCreated             Id LevelDisplayName Message     PSComputerName                                            
           
     -----------             -- ---------------- -------     --------------                                            
           
     5/14/2012 7:26:04 PM   400 Information      Engine stat Server02                                                  
      
     5/14/2012 7:26:03 PM   600 Information      Provider "W Server02                                                  
      
     5/14/2012 7:26:03 PM   600 Information      Provider "C Server02                                                  
      
     5/14/2012 7:26:03 PM   600 Information      Provider "V Server02                                                  
      



  STATE AND AVAILABILITY
     The State and Availability properties of a disconnected PSSession
     tell you whether the session is available for you to reconnect to it.
  
     When a PSSession is connected to the current session, its state is
     Opened and its availability is Available. When you disconnect from 
     the PSSession, the PSSession state is Disconnected and its Availability
     is none.

     However, the value of the State property is relative to the current 
     session. Therefore, a value of Disconnected means that the PSSession
     is not connected to the current session. However, it does not mean
     that the PSSession is disconnected from all sessions. It might be
     connected to a different session. 

     To determine whether you can connect or reconnect to the PSSession, 
     use the Availability property. An Availability value of None indicates
     that you can connect to the session. A value of Busy indicates that
     you cannot connect to the PSSession because it is connected to another
     session.

     The following example is run in two sessions (Windows PowerShell
     console windows) on the same computer. Note the changing values of the
     State and Availability properties in each session as the PSSession is
     disconnected and reconnected.


         #Session 1:
         PS C:\> New-PSSession -ComputerName Server30 -Name Test

         Id Name       ComputerName    State         ConfigurationName     Availability
         -- ----       ------------    -----         -----------------     ------------
         1  Test       Server30        Opened        Microsoft.PowerShell     Available

         #Session 2: 
         PS C:\> Get-PSSession -ComputerName Server30 -Name Test

         Id Name       ComputerName    State         ConfigurationName     Availability
         -- ----       ------------    -----         -----------------     ------------
         1 Test        Server30        Disconnected  Microsoft.PowerShell          Busy



         #Session 1
         PS C:\> Get-PSSession -ComputerName Server30 -Name Test | Disconnect-PSSession

         Id Name       ComputerName    State         ConfigurationName     Availability
         -- ----       ------------    -----         -----------------     ------------
          1 Test       Server30        Disconnected  Microsoft.PowerShell          None

         #Session 2
         PS C:\> Get-PSSession -ComputerName Server30 

         Id Name       ComputerName    State         ConfigurationName     Availability
         -- ----       ------------    -----         -----------------     ------------
          1 Test       Server30        Disconnected  Microsoft.PowerShell          None



         #Session 2
         PS C:\> Connect-PSSession -ComputerName Server01 -Name Test

         Id Name       ComputerName    State         ConfigurationName     Availability
         -- ----       ------------    -----         -----------------     ------------
         3 Test        Server30        Opened        Microsoft.PowerShell     Available

         #Session 1
         PS C:\> Get-PSSession -ComputerName Server30 

         Id Name       ComputerName    State         ConfigurationName     Availability
         -- ----       ------------    -----         -----------------     ------------
          1 Test       Server30        Disconnected  Microsoft.PowerShell          Busy



  IDLE TIMEOUT
    Disconnected sessions are maintained on the remote computer until
    you delete them, such as by using the Remove-PSSession cmdlet, or
    they time out. The IdleTimeout property of a PSSession determines
    how long a disconnected session is maintained before it is deleted.

    PSSessions are idle when the "heartbeat thread" receives no response.
    Disconnecting a session makes it idle and starts the Idle Timeout
    clock, even if commands are still running in the disconnected session. 
    Windows PowerShell considers disconnected sessions to be active, but
    idle.

    When creating and disconnecting sessions, verify that the idle
    timeout in the PSSession is long enough to maintain the session
    for your needs, but not so long that it consumes unnecessary 
    resources on the remote computer.

    The IdleTimeoutMs property of the session configuration
    determines the default idle timeout of sessions that use the 
    session configuration. You can override the default value, but
    the value that you use cannot exceed the MaxIdleTimeoutMs 
    property of the session configuration.

    To find the value of the IdleTimeoutMs and MaxIdleTimeoutMs
    values of a session configuration, use the following command 
    format.

      Get-PSSessionConfiguration | Format-Table Name, IdleTimeoutMs, MaxIdleTimeoutMs

    You can override the default value in the session configuration and
    set the idle timeout of a PSSession when you create a PSSession and
    when you disconnect. 

    If you are a member of the Administrators group on the remote computer, 
    you can also create and change the IdleTimeoutMs and MaxIdleTimeoutMs 
    properties of session configurations.


    NOTES: 
          The idle timeout value of session configurations and session
          options is in milliseconds. The idle timeout value of sessions
          and session configuration options is in seconds.

          You can set the idle timeout of a PSSession when you create the
          PSSession (New-PSSession, Invoke-Command) and when you disconnect
          from it (Disconnect-PSSession). However, you cannot change the
          IdleTimeout value when you connect to the PSSession 
         (Connect-PSSession) or get results (Receive-PSSession).

          The Connect-PSSession and Receive-PSSession cmdlets have a
          SessionOption parameter that takes a SessionOption object, 
          such as one returned by the New-PSSessionOption cmdlet. However,
          the IdleTimeout value in SessionOption object and the IdleTimeout
          value in the $PSSessionOption preference variable do not change
          the value of the IdleTimeout of the PSSession in a Connect-PSSession
          or Receive-PSSession command. 


    -- To create a PSSession with a particular idle timeout value, create
       a $PSSessionOption preference variable. Set the value of the  
       IdleTimeout property to the desired value (in milliseconds).

       When you create PSSessions, the values in $PSSessionOption variable
       take precedence over the values in the session configuration.
      

       For example, this command sets an idle timeout of 48 hours.
         PS C:\> $PSSessionOption = New-PSSessionOption -IdleTimeoutMSec 172800000 



    -- To create a PSSession with a particular idle timeout value, use
       the IdleTimeoutMSec parameter of the New-PSSessionOption cmdlet. 
       Then, use the session option in the value of the SessionOption
       parameter of the New-PSSession or Invoke-Command cmdlets. 

       The values set when creating the session take precedence over the
       values set in the $PSSessionOption preference variable and the
       session configuration.

       For example:

         PS C:\> $o = New-PSSessionOption -IdleTimeoutMSec 172800000 
         PS C:\> New-PSSession -SessionOption $o



    -- To change a the idle timeout of a PSSession when disconnecting, 
       use the IdleTimeoutSec parameter of the Disconnect-PSSession 
       cmdlet.

       For example:

         PS C:\> Disconnect-PSSession -IdleTimeoutSec 172800 



    -- To create a session configuration with a particular idle timeout
       and maximum idle timeout, use the IdleTimeoutSec and MaxIdleTimeoutSec
       parameters of the New-PSTransportOption cmdlet. Then, use the
       transport option in the value of the TransportOption parameter
       of Register-PSSessionConfiguration.

       For example:

         PS C:\> $o = New-PSTransportOption -IdleTimeoutSec 172800 -MaxIdleTimeoutSec 259200 
         PS C:\> Register-PSSessionConfiguration -Name Test -TransportOption $o


    -- To change the default idle timeout and maximum idle timeout of
       a session configuration, use the IdleTimeoutSec and MaxIdleTimeoutSec
       parameters of the New-PSTransportOption cmdlet. Then, use the
       transport option in the value of the TransportOption parameter
       of Set-PSSessionConfiguration.
       For example:

         PS C:\> $o = New-PSTransportOption -IdleTimeoutSec 172800 -MaxIdleTimeoutSec 259200
         PS C:\> Set-PSSessionConfiguration -Name Test -TransportOption $o




  OUTPUT BUFFERING MODE
    The output buffering mode of a PSSession determines how command
    output is managed when the output buffer of the PSSession is full.

    In a disconnected session, the output buffering mode effectively
    determines whether the command continues to run while the session
    is disconnected. 


    Valid values:

    -- Block: When the output buffer is full, execution is suspended
              until the buffer is clear.

    -- Drop:  When the output buffer is full, execution continues. 
              As new output is generated, the oldest output is
              discarded.


    Block, the default value, preserves data, but might interrupt
    the command    


    A value of Drop allows the command to complete, although data might
    be lost. When using the Drop value, redirect the command output to
    a file on disk. This value is recommended for disconnected sessions.


    The OutputBufferingMode property of the session configuration
    determines the default output buffering mode of sessions that 
    use the session configuration. 

    To find the value of the OutputBufferingMode of a session 
    configuration, use the following command formats.

      (Get-PSSessionConfiguration <ConfigurationName>).OutputBufferingMode

    -or-

      Get-PSSessionConfiguration | Format-Table Name, OutputBufferingMode



    You can override the default value in the session configuration and set
    the output buffering mode of a PSSession when you create a PSSession,
    when you disconnect, and when you reconnect. 

    If you are a member of the Administrators group on the remote computer, 
    you can also create and change the output buffering mode of session
    configurations.


    -- To create a PSSession with an output buffering mode of Drop, create
       a $PSSessionOption preference variable in which the value of the 
       OutputBufferingMode property is Drop. 

       When you create PSSessions, the values in $PSSessionOption variable
       take precedence over the values in the session configuration.
      

       For example:

         PS C:\> $PSSessionOption = New-PSSessionOption -OutputBufferingMode Drop


    -- To create a PSSession with an output buffering mode of Drop, use
       the OutputBufferingMode parameter of the New-PSSessionOption
       cmdlet to create a session option with a value of Drop. Then, use
       the session option in the value of the SessionOption parameter of 
       the New-PSSession or Invoke-Command cmdlets. 

       The values set when creating the session take precedence over the
       values set in the $PSSessionOption preference variable and the session
       configuration.

       For example:

         PS C:\> $o = New-PSSessionOption -OutputBufferingMode Drop
         PS C:\> New-PSSession -SessionOption $o


    -- To change a the output buffering mode of a PSSession when 
       disconnecting, use the OutputBufferingMode parameter of the 
       Disconnect-PSSession cmdlet.

       For example:

         PS C:\> Disconnect-PSSession -OutputBufferingMode Drop


    -- To change a the output buffering mode of a PSSession when 
       reconnecting, use the OutputBufferingMode parameter of the
       New-PSSessionOption cmdlet to create a session option with
       a value of Drop. Then, use the session option in the value of the 
       SessionOption parameter of Connect-PSSession or Receive-PSSession.

       For example:

         PS C:\> $o = New-PSSessionOption -OutputBufferingMode Drop
         PS C:\> Connect-PSSession -Cn Server01 -Name Test -SessionOption $o


    -- To create a session configuration with a default output buffering
       mode of Drop, use the OutputBufferingMode parameter of the
       New-PSTransportOption cmdlet to create a transport option object
       with a value of Drop. Then, use the transport option in the value of
       the TransportOption parameter of Register-PSSessionConfiguration.

       For example:

         PS C:\> $o = New-PSTransportOption -OutputBufferingMode Drop
         PS C:\> Register-PSSessionConfiguration -Name Test -TransportOption $o


    -- To change the default output buffering mode of a session 
       configuration, use the OutputBufferingMode parameter of the
       New-PSTransportOption cmdlet to create a transport option with a
       value of Drop. Then, use the Transport option in the value of the 
       SessionOption parameter of Set-PSSessionConfiguration.

       For example:

         PS C:\> $o = New-PSTransportOption -OutputBufferingMode Drop
         PS C:\> Set-PSSessionConfiguration -Name Test -TransportOption $o

   


  DISCONNECTING LOOPBACK SESSIONS
    "Loopback sessions" or "local sessions" are PSSessions that
    originate and terminate on the same computer. Like other 
    PSSessions, active loopback sessions are maintained on the
    computer on the remote end of the connection (the local
    computer), so you can disconnect from and reconnect to
    loopback sessions.

    By default, loopback sessions are created with a network security
    token that does not permit commands run in the session to access
    other computers. You can reconnect to loopback sessions that have a 
    network security token from any session on the local computer or a 
    remote computer.

    However, if you use the EnableNetworkAccess parameter of the
    New-PSSession, Enter-PSSession, or Invoke-Command cmdlet, the
    loopback session is created with an interactive security token.
    The interactive token enables commands that run in the loopback 
    session to get data from other computers. 

    You can disconnect loopback sessions with interactive tokens and
    then reconnect to them from the same session or a different session
    on the same computer. However, to prevent malicious access, you can
    reconnect to loopback sessions with interactive tokens only from the
    computer on which they were created.


  WAITING FOR JOBS IN DISCONNECTED SESSIONS
    The Wait-Job cmdlet waits until a job completes and then
    returns to the command prompt or the next command. By default,
    Wait-Job returns if the session in which a job is running is
    disconnected. To direct the Wait-Job cmdlet to wait until the 
    session is reconnected (in the Opened state), use the Force
    parameter. For more information, see Wait-Job.


  ROBUST SESSIONS AND UNINTENTIONAL DISCONNECTION 
    Occasionally, a PSSession might be disconnected unintentionally
    due to a computer failure or network outage. Windows PowerShell
    attempts to recover the PSSession, but its success depends upon 
    the severity and duration of the cause. 

    The state of an unintentionally disconnected PSSession might
    be Broken or Closed, but it might also be Disconnected. If 
    the value of State is Disconnected, you can use the same 
    techniques to manage the PSSession as you would if the 
    session were disconnected intentionally. For example, you 
    can use the Connect-PSSession cmdlet to reconnect to the session
    and the Receive-PSSession cmdlet to get results of commands that
    ran while the session was disconnected.

    If you close (exit) the session in which a PSSession was
    created while commands are running in the PSSession, Windows
    PowerShell maintains the PSSession in the Disconnected state
    on the remote computer. If you close (exit) the session in
    which a PSSession was created, but no commands are running
    in the PSSession, Windows PowerShell does not attempt to
    maintain the PSSession.


  KEYWORDS
    about_Disconnected_Sessions

  SEE ALSO
    about_Jobs
    about_Remote
    about_Remote_Variables
    about_PSSessions
    about_Session_Configurations
    Disconnect-PSSession
    Connect-PSSession
    Get-PSSession
    Receive-PSSession
    Invoke-Command












