TOPIC
    about_Remote

SHORT DESCRIPTION
    Describes how to run remote commands in Windows PowerShell.


LONG DESCRIPTION
    You can run remote commands on a single computer or on multiple
    computers by using a temporary or persistent connection. You can also
    start an interactive session with a single remote computer.
    
    This topic provides a series of examples to show you how to
    run different types of remote command. After you try these basic
    commands, read the Help topics that describe each cmdlet that is
    used in these commands. The topics provide the details and explain
    how you can modify the commands to meet your needs.

    Note: To use Windows PowerShell remoting, the local and remote computers
          must be configured for remoting. For more information, see
          about_Remote_Requirements. 
          

 HOW TO START AN INTERACTIVE SESSION (ENTER-PSSESSION)

     The easiest way to run remote commands is to start an
     interactive session with a remote computer. 

     When the session starts, the commands that you type run on the
     remote computer, just as though you typed them directly
     on the remote computer. You can connect to only one
     computer in each interactive session. 

     To start an interactive session, use the Enter-PSSession
     cmdlet. The following command starts an interactive session
     with the Server01 computer:

Enter-PSSession Server01

     The command prompt changes to indicate that you are connected
     to the Server01 computer.

Server01\PS> 

     Now, you can type commands on the Server01 computer. 

     To end the interactive session, type:

Exit-PSSession


     For more information, see Enter-PSSession.

      

 HOW TO USE CMDLETS THAT HAVE A COMPUTERNAME PARAMETER TO GET REMOTE DATA

    Several cmdlets have a ComputerName parameter that lets you
    get objects from remote computers. 

    Because these cmdlets do not use WS-Management-based Windows PowerShell
    remoting, you can use the ComputerName parameter of these cmdlets on any
    computer that is running Windows PowerShell. The computers do not have to
    be configured for Windows PowerShell remoting, and the computers do not
    have to meet the system requirements for remoting. 

    The following cmdlets have a ComputerName parameter:
 
        Clear-EventLog    Limit-EventLog
        Get-Counter       New-EventLog
        Get-EventLog      Remove-EventLog
        Get-HotFix        Restart-Computer
        Get-Process       Show-EventLog
        Get-Service       Stop-Computer
        Get-WinEvent      Test-Connection
        Get-WmiObject     Write-EventLog

  
    For example, the following command gets the services on
    the Server01 remote computer:

Get-Service -ComputerName Server01


    Typically, cmdlets that support remoting without special configuration
    have a ComputerName parameter and do not have a Session parameter. To
    find these cmdlets in your session, type:

        Get-Command | where { $_.Parameters.Keys -contains "ComputerName" -and $_.Parameters.Keys -NotContains 
"Session"}
 

 HOW TO RUN A REMOTE COMMAND

    To run other commands on remote computers, use the
    Invoke-Command cmdlet.

    To run a single command or a few unrelated commands, use the
    ComputerName parameter of Invoke-Command to specify the remote
    computers. Use the ScriptBlock parameter to specify the command.

    For example, the following command runs a Get-Culture command
    on the Server01 computer.

Invoke-Command -ComputerName Server01 -ScriptBlock {Get-Culture}

    The ComputerName parameter is designed for situation in which you run
    a single command or several unrelated commands on one or many computers.
    To establish a persistent connection to a remote computer, use
    the Session parameter.

 
 HOW TO CREATE A PERSISTENT CONNECTION (PSSESSION)

    When you use the ComputerName parameter of the Invoke-Command
    cmdlet, Windows PowerShell establishes a connection just for the
    command. Then, it closes the connection when the command is complete. Any
    variables or functions that are defined in the command are lost.

    To create a persistent connection to a remote computer, use the
    New-PSSession cmdlet. For example, the following command creates
    PSSessions on the Server01 and Server02 computers and then saves the
    PSSessions in the $s variable.

$s = New-PSSession -ComputerName Server01, Server02


 HOW TO RUN COMMANDS IN A PSSESSION
  
    With a PSSession, you can run a series of remote commands that
    share data, like functions, aliases, and the values of variables.
    To run commands in a PSSession, use the Session parameter of the
    Invoke-Command cmdlet. 

    For example, the following command uses the Invoke-Command cmdlet
    to run a Get-Process command in the PSSessions on the Server01
    and Server02 computers. The command saves the processes in a $p
    variable in each PSSession.

        Invoke-Command -Session $s -ScriptBlock {$p = Get-Process}

    Because the PSSession uses a persistent connection, you can run
    another command in the same PSSession that uses the $p variable.
    The following command counts the number of processes saved in $p.

        Invoke-Command -Session $s -ScriptBlock {$p.count}
    

 HOW TO RUN A REMOTE COMMAND ON MULTIPLE COMPUTERS

    To run a remote command on multiple computers, type all of
    the computer names in the value of the ComputerName parameter of
    Invoke-Command. Separate the names with commas.

    For example, the following command runs a Get-Culture command
    on three computers:

Invoke-Command -ComputerName S1, S2, S3 -ScriptBlock {Get-Culture}

    You can also run a command in multiple PSSessions. The following
    commands create PSSessions on the Server01, Server02, and Server03
    computers and then run a Get-Culture command in each of the PSSessions.

        $s = New-PSSession -ComputerName S1, S2, S3
Invoke-Command -Session $s -ScriptBlock {Get-Culture}


    To include the local computer list of computers, type the name of 
    the local computer, type a dot (.), or type  "localhost". 

Invoke-Command -ComputerName S1, S2, S3, localhost -ScriptBlock {Get-Culture}


 HOW TO RUN A SCRIPT ON REMOTE COMPUTERS

    To run a local script on remote computers, use the
    FilePath parameter of Invoke-Command.

    For example, the following command runs the Sample.ps1 script
    on the S1 and S2 computers:

        Invoke-Command -ComputerName S1, S2 -FilePath C:\Test\Sample.ps1

    The results of the script are returned to the local computer. You
    do not need to copy any files.
  

 HOW TO STOP A REMOTE COMMAND

   To interrupt a command, press CTRL+C. The interrupt request is
   passed to the remote computer where it terminates the remote command.



FOR MORE INFORMATION

    -- For information about the system requirements for remoting,
       see about_Remote_Requirements.

    -- For help in formatting remote output, see about_Remote_Output.

    -- For information about how remoting works, how to manage remote
       data, special configurations, security issues, and other frequently
       asked questions, see about_Remote_FAQ.

    -- For help in resolving remoting errors, see about_Remote_Troubleshooting.

    -- For information about PSSessions and persistent connections, see
       about_PSSessions.

    -- For information about Windows PowerShell background jobs, see
       about_Jobs.

KEYWORDS
    about_Remoting

SEE ALSO
    about_PSSessions
    about_Remote_Disconnected_Sessions
    about_Remote_Requirements
    about_Remote_FAQ
    about_Remote_TroubleShooting
    about_Remote_Variables
    Enter-PSSession 
    Invoke-Command
    New-PSSession












