TOPIC
    about_Run_With_PowerShell

SHORT DESCRIPTION
    Explains how to use the "Run with PowerShell" feature to run 
    a script from a file system drive.

LONG DESCRIPTION
    Beginning in Windows PowerShell 3.0, you can use the "Run with
    PowerShell" feature to run scripts from File Explorer in Windows 8
    and Windows Server 2012 and from Windows Explorer in earlier 
    versions of Windows. 

    The "Run with PowerShell" feature is designed to run scripts 
    that do not have required parameters and do not return output 
    to the command prompt. 

    When you use the "Run with PowerShell" feature, the Windows 
    PowerShell console window appears only briefly, if at all.
    You cannot interact with it.


    To use the "Run with PowerShell" feature:

        In File Explorer (or Windows Explorer), right-click the 
        script file name and then select "Run with PowerShell".

    The "Run with PowerShell" feature starts a Windows PowerShell 
    session that has an execution policy of Bypass, runs the 
    script, and closes the session.

    It runs a command that has the following format:
        PowerShell.exe -File <FileName> -ExecutionPolicy Bypass


    "Run with PowerShell" sets the Bypass execution policy only 
    for the session (the current instance of the PowerShell process) 
    in which the script runs. This feature does not change the execution
    policy for the computer or the user. 

    The "Run with PowerShell" feature is affected only by the AllSigned
    execution policy. If the AllSigned execution policy is effective for
    the computer or the user, "Run with PowerShell" runs only signed 
    scripts. "Run with PowerShell" is not affected by any other execution 
    policy. For more information, see about_Execution_Policies.

    Troubleshooting Note: Run with PowerShell command might prompt you
    to confirm the execution policy change.
   
SEE ALSO
    about_ExecutionPolicies
    about_Group_Policy_Settings
    about_Scripts
    "Running Scripts" (http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=257680)














