TOPIC
    about_Requires

SHORT DESCRIPTION
    Prevents a script from running without the required elements.

LONG DESCRIPTION
    The #Requires statement prevents a script from running unless the Windows 
    PowerShell version, modules, snap-ins, and module and snap-in version
    prerequisites are met. If the prerequisites are not met, Windows PowerShell
    does not run the script. 

    You can use #Requires statements in any script. You cannot use them in 
    functions, cmdlets, or snap-ins. 

  SYNTAX 
          #Requires -Version <N>[.<n>] 
          #Requires –PSSnapin <PSSnapin-Name> [-Version <N>[.<n>]]
          #Requires -Modules { <Module-Name> | <Hashtable> } 
          #Requires –ShellId <ShellId>

  RULES FOR USE 

      - The #Requires statement must be the first item on a line in a script.
      - A script can include more than one #Requires statement. 
      - The #Requires statements can appear on any line in a script.

  PARAMETERS
  -Version <N>[.<n>]
      Specifies the minimum version of Windows PowerShell that the script 
      requires. Enter a major version number and optional minor version number.

      For example: 
        #Requires -Version 3.0


  -PSSnapin <PSSnapin-Name> [-Version <N>[.<n>]]
      Specifies a Windows PowerShell snap-in that the script requires. Enter the snap-in
      name and an optional version number.

      For example: 
        #Requires –PSSnapin DiskSnapin -Version 1.2


  -Modules <Module-Name> | <Hashtable>  
      Specifies Windows PowerShell modules that the script requires. Enter the module
      name and an optional version number. The Modules parameter is introduced in
      Windows PowerShell 3.0.

      If the required modules are not in the current session, Windows
      PowerShell imports them. If the modules cannot be imported,
      Windows PowerShell throws a terminating error.

      For each module, type the module name (<String>) or a hash table
      with the following keys. The value can be a combination of strings
      and hash tables.  

          -- ModuleName. This key is required.
          -- ModuleVersion. This key is required.
          -- GUID. This key is optional.

      For example,
        #Requires -Modules PSWorkflow, @{ModuleName="PSScheduledJob";ModuleVersion=1.0.0.0}  


  -ShellId
      Specifies the shell that the script requires. Enter the shell ID.
          
      For example,
        #Requires –ShellId MyLocalShell

      

  EXAMPLES

      The following script has two #Requires statements. If the requirements 
      specified in both statements are not met, the script does not run. 
      Each #Requires statement must be the first item on a line:

          #Requires –Modules PSWorkflow
          #Requires –Version 3
          Param
         (
             [parameter(Mandatory=$true)]
             [String[]]
             $Path
         )
         ...


  NOTES   
      In Windows PowerShell 3.0, the Windows PowerShell Core packages appear
      as modules in sessions started by using the InitialSessionState.CreateDefault2
      method, such as sessions started in the Windows PowerShell console. Otherwise,
      they appear as snap-ins. The exception is Microsoft.PowerShell.Core, which                 
      is always a snap-in.

SEE ALSO
    about_Automatic_Variables 
    about_Language_Keywords
    about_PSSnapins
    get-PSSnapin












