TOPIC
    about_aliases

SHORT DESCRIPTION
    Describes how to use alternate names for cmdlets and commands in Windows
    PowerShell. 

LONG DESCRIPTION
    An alias is an alternate name or nickname for a cmdlet or for a command
    element, such as a function, script, file, or executable file. You
    can use the alias instead of the command name in any Windows PowerShell
    commands.
    
    To create an alias, use the New-Alias cmdlet. For example, the following
    command creates the "gas" alias for the Get-AuthenticodeSignature cmdlet:

        New-Alias -Name gas -Value Get-AuthenticodeSignature

    After you create the alias for the cmdlet name, you can use the alias 
    instead of the cmdlet name. For example, to get the Authenticode signature
    for the SqlScript.ps1 file, type:

        Get-AuthenticodeSignature SqlScript.ps1

    Or, type:

        gas SqlScript.ps1


    If you create "word" as the alias for Microsoft Office Word, you can type
    "word" instead of the following:


        "C:\Program Files\Microsoft Office\Office11\Winword.exe" 

BUILT-IN ALIASES
    Windows PowerShell includes a set of built-in aliases, including "cd" and
    "chdir" for the Set-Location cmdlet, and "ls" and "dir" for the
    Get-ChildItem cmdlet. 

    To get all the aliases on the computer, including the built-in aliases,
    type:

        Get-Alias


ALIAS CMDLETS
    Windows PowerShell includes the following cmdlets, which are designed for
    working with aliases: 

        - Get-Alias. Gets all the aliases in the current session.
        - New-Alias. Creates a new alias.
        - Set-Alias. Creates or changes an alias.
        - Export-Alias. Exports one or more aliases to a file.
        - Import-Alias. Imports an alias file into Windows PowerShell. 

    For detailed information about the cmdlets, type:

Get-Help <cmdlet-Name> -Detailed

    For example, type:

Get-Help Export-Alias -Detailed

CREATING AN ALIAS
    To create a new alias, use the New-Alias cmdlet. For example, to create the
    "gh" alias for Get-Help, type:

New-Alias -Name gh -Value Get-Help

    You can use the alias in commands, just as you would use the full cmdlet
    name, and you can use the alias with parameters.

    For example, to get detailed Help for the Get-WmiObject cmdlet, type:

Get-Help Get-WmiObject -Detailed

    Or, type:

gh Get-WmiObject -Detailed

SAVING ALIASES
    The aliases that you create are saved only in the current session. To use
    the aliases in a different session, add the alias to your Windows 
    PowerShell profile. Or, use the Export-Alias cmdlet to save the aliases to
    a file. 
    
    For more information, type:

        Get-Help about_Profiles

GETTING ALIASES
    To get all the aliases in the current session, including the built-in
    aliases, the aliases in your Windows PowerShell profiles, and the aliases
    that you have created in the current session, type:

Get-Alias
  
    To get particular aliases, use the Name parameter of the Get-Alias cmdlet.
    For example, to get aliases that begin with "p", type:

Get-Alias -Name p*

    To get the aliases for a particular item, use the Definition parameter.
    For example, to get the aliases for the Get-ChildItem cmdlet type:

Get-Alias -Definition Get-ChildItem

 GET-ALIAS OUTPUT

     Get-Alias returns only one type of object, an AliasInfo object 
     (System.Management.Automation.AliasInfo). However, beginning in
     Windows PowerShell 3.0, the name of aliases that don't include a
     hyphen, such as "cd" are displayed in the following format:
 
         <alias> -> <definition>

     For example,

         ac -> Add-Content  

     This makes it very quick and easy to get the information that you
     need. 

     The arrow-based alias name format is not used for aliases that
     include a hyphen. These are likely to be preferred substitute 
     names for cmdlets and functions, instead of typical abbreviations
     or nicknames, and the author might not want them to be as evident.


ALTERNATE NAMES FOR COMMANDS WITH PARAMETERS
    You can assign an alias to a cmdlet, script, function, or executable file.
    However, you cannot assign an alias to a command and its parameters.
    For example, you can assign an alias to the Get-Eventlog cmdlet, but you
    cannot assign an alias to the "Get-Eventlog -LogName System" command.

    However, you can create a function that includes the command. To create a
    function, type the word "function" followed by a name for the function.
    Type the command, and enclose it in braces ({}).

    For example, the following command creates the syslog function. This
    function represents the "Get-Eventlog -LogName System" command:

function syslog {Get-Eventlog -LogName System}

    You can now type "syslog" instead of the command. And, you can create
    aliases for the syslog function.

    For more information about functions, type:

Get-Help about_Functions

ALIAS OBJECTS
     Windows PowerShell aliases are represented by objects that are instances
     of the System.Management.Automation.AliasInfo class. For more information
     about this type of object, see "AliasInfo Class" in the Microsoft 
     Developer Network (MSDN) library at 
     http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=143644.

     To view the properties and methods of the alias objects, get the
     aliases. Then, pipe them to the Get-Member cmdlet. For example:

Get-Alias | Get-Member

     To view the values of the properties of a specific alias, such as the 
     "dir" alias, get the alias. Then, pipe it to the Format-List cmdlet. For
     example, the following command gets the "dir" alias. Next, the command
     pipes the alias to the Format-List cmdlet. Then, the command uses the 
     Property parameter of Format-List with a wildcard character (*) to display
     all the properties of the "dir" alias. The following command performs
     these tasks:

Get-Alias -Name dir | Format-List -Property *

WINDOWS POWERSHELL ALIAS PROVIDER
    Windows PowerShell includes the Alias provider. The Alias provider lets you
    view the aliases in Windows PowerShell as though they were on a file system
    drive. 

    The Alias provider exposes the Alias: drive. To go into the Alias: drive,
    type:

Set-Location Alias:

    To view the contents of the drive, type:

Get-ChildItem

    To view the contents of the drive from another Windows PowerShell drive,
    begin the path with the drive name. Include the colon (:). For example:

Get-ChildItem -Path Alias:

    To get information about a particular alias, type the drive name and
    the alias name. Or, type a name pattern. For example, to get all the 
    aliases that begin with "p", type:

Get-ChildItem -Path Alias:p*

    For more information about the Windows PowerShell Alias provider,
    type:

Get-Help Alias


SEE ALSO

    New-Alias
    Get-Alias
    set-alias
    export-alias
    import-alias
    get-psprovider
    get-psdrive
    about_functions
    about_profiles
    about_providers












