TOPIC
    about_Group_Policy_Settings

SHORT DESCRIPTION
    Describes the Group Policy settings for Windows PowerShell

LONG DESCRIPTION

    Windows PowerShell includes Group Policy settings to help you define
    consistent option values for servers in an enterprise environment. 

    The Windows PowerShell Group Policy settings are in the following
    Group Policy paths:

        Computer Configuration\Administrative Templates\Windows Components\Windows PowerShell
        User Configuration\Administrative Templates\Windows Components\Windows PowerShell    

    Group policy settings in the User Configuration path take precedence
    over Group Policy settings in the Computer Configuration path.


    The policies are as follows:

        Turn on Script Execution:  Sets the Windows PowerShell execution
                                   policy.
        Turn on Module Logging:    Sets the LogPipelineExecutionDetails 
                                   property of modules.
        Set the default source path for Update-Help: 
                                   Sets the source for UpdatableHelp to
                                   a directory, not the Internet.


    To download spreadsheets that list all of the Group Policy settings for 
    each version of Windows, see "Group Policy Settings Reference for Windows
    and Windows Server" in the Microsoft Download Center at
    http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=261775
 
  TURN ON SCRIPT EXECUTION
    The "Turn on Script Execution" policy setting sets the execution policy
    for computers and users, which determines which scripts are permitted to
    run.

    If you enable the policy setting, you can select from among the following
    policy settings.

        -- "Allow only signed scripts" allows scripts to execute only if they
           are signed by a trusted publisher. This policy setting is equivalent
           to the AllSigned execution policy.

        -- "Allow local scripts and remote signed scripts" allows all local
           scripts to run. Scripts that originate from the Internet must be
           signed by a trusted publisher. This policy setting is equivalent
           to the RemoteSigned execution policy.

        -- "Allow all scripts" allows all scripts to run. This policy
           setting is equivalent to the Unrestricted execution policy.


    If you disable this policy setting, no scripts are allowed to run.
    This policy setting is equivalent to the Restricted execution policy.

    If you disable or do not configure this policy setting, the execution
    policy that is set for the computer or user by the Set-ExecutionPolicy
    cmdlet determines whether scripts  are permitted to run. The default
    value is Restricted.

    For more information, see about_Execution_Policies 
    (http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkID=135170).


  TURN ON MODULE LOGGING
    The "Turn on Module Logging" policy setting turns on logging for 
    selected Windows PowerShell modules. The setting is effective in
    all sessions on all affected computers.

    If you enable this policy setting and specify one or more modules,
    pipeline execution events for the specified modules are recorded in
    the Windows PowerShell log in Event Viewer. 

    If you disable this policy setting, logging of execution events is
    disabled for all Windows PowerShell modules. 

    If this policy setting is not configured, the LogPipelineExecutionDetails
    property of each module or snap-in determines whether the execution
    events of a module or snap-in are logged. By default, the
    LogPipelineExecutionDetails property of all modules and snap-ins is set
    to False.

    To turn on module logging for a module, use the following command format.
    The module must be imported into the session and the setting is effective
    only in the current session.

        PS C:\>Import-Module <Module-Name>
        PS C:\>(Get-Module <Module-Name>).LogPipelineExecutionDetails = $true

    To turn on module logging for all sessions on a particular computer,
    add the previous commands to the all-users Windows PowerShell profile
    ($Profile.AllUsers.AllHosts).

    For more information about module logging, see about_Modules 
    (http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkID=144311).


  SET THE DEFAULT SOURCE PATH FOR UPDATE-HELP
    The "Set the Default Source Path for Update-Help" policy setting sets a
    default value for the SourcePath parameter of the Update-Help cmdlet. 
    This setting prevents users from using the Update-Help cmdlet to download
    help files from the Internet.

    NOTE: The "Set the default source path for Update-Help" Group
          Policy setting appears under Computer Configuration and
          User Configuration. However, only the Group Policy setting
          under Computer Configuration is effective. The Group Policy
          setting under User Configuration is ignored. 

    The Update-Help cmdlet downloads and installs the newest help files for
    Windows PowerShell modules and installs them on the computer. By default,
    Update-Help downloads new help files from an Internet location specified
    by the module.
    
    However, you can use the Save-Help cmdlet to download the newest help
    files to a file system location, such as a network share, and then use
    the Update-Help cmdlet to get the help files from the file system
    location and install them on the computer. The SourcePath parameter of
    the Update-Help cmdlet specifies the file system location.
  
    By providing a default value for the SourcePath parameter, this Group
    Policy setting implicitly adds the SourcePath parameter to all Update-Help
    commands. Users can override the particular file system location specified
    as the default value by entering a different file system location. But they
    cannot remove the SourcePath parameter from the Update-Help command. 

    If you enable this policy setting, you can specify a default value for the
    SourcePath parameter. Enter a file system location.

    If this policy setting is disabled or not configured,  there is no
    default value for the SourcePath parameter of the Update-Help cmdlet. 
    Users can download help from the Internet or from any file system
    location.

    For more information, see about_Updatable_Help 
    (http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkID=235801).


KEYWORDS
    about_Group_Policies
    about_GroupPolicy
    
SEE ALSO
    about_Execution_Policies
    about_Modules
    about_Updatable_Help

    Get-ExecutionPolicy
    Set-ExecutionPolicy
    Get-Module
    Update-Help
    Save-Help













