about_Quoting_Rules
TOPIC
    about_Quoting_Rules

SHORT DESCRIPTION
    Describes rules for using single and double quotation marks 
    in Windows PowerShell.


LONG DESCRIPTION
    Quotation marks are used to specify a literal string. You can enclose a
    string in single quotation marks (') or double quotation marks (").
 
    Quotation marks are also used to create a here-string. A here-string is a
    single-quoted or double-quoted string in which quotation marks are
    interpreted literally. A here-string can span multiple lines. All the
    lines in a here-string are interpreted as strings, even though they are
    not enclosed in quotation marks.

    In commands to remote computers, quotation marks define the parts of
    the command that are run on the remote computer. In a remote session,
    quotation marks also determine whether the variables in a command are
    interpreted first on the local computer or on the remote computer.


 SINGLE AND DOUBLE-QUOTED STRINGS
    When you enclose a string in double quotation marks (a double-quoted
    string), variable names that are preceded by a dollar sign ($) are 
    replaced with the variable's value before the string is passed to the
    command for processing.

    For example:

        $i = 5
        "The value of $i is $i."

    The output of this command is: 
        The value of 5 is 5.

    Also, in a double-quoted string, expressions are evaluated, and the 
    result is inserted in the string. For example:

        "The value of $(2+3) is 5."

    The output of this command is:

        The value of 5 is 5.

    When you enclose a string in single-quotation marks (a single-quoted 
    string), the string is passed to the command exactly as you type it. 
    No substitution is performed. For example:

        $i = 5
        'The value of $i is $i.'

    The output of this command is: 

        The value $i is $i.

    Similarly, expressions in single-quoted strings are not evaluated. They
    are interpreted as literals. For example:

        'The value of $(2+3) is 5.'

    The output of this command is:

        The value of $(2+3) is 5.

    To prevent the substitution of a variable value in a double-quoted 
    string, use the backtick character (`)(ASCII 96), which is the 
    Windows PowerShell escape character.

    In the following example, the backtick character that precedes the first 
    $i variable prevents Windows PowerShell from replacing the variable name 
    with its value. For example:

        $i = 5
        "The value of `$i is $i."

    The output of this command is: 

        The value $i is 5.
     
    
    To make double-quotation marks appear in a string, enclose the entire
    string in single quotation marks. For example:

        'As they say, "live and learn."'

    The output of this command is:

        As they say, "live and learn."


    You can also enclose a single-quoted string in a double-quoted string. 
    For example:

        "As they say, 'live and learn.'"

    The output of this command is:

        As they say, 'live and learn.'


    Or, double the quotation marks around a double-quoted phrase. For 
    example:

        "As they say, ""live and learn."""

    The output of this command is:

        As they say, "live and learn."

    To include a single quotation mark in a single-quoted string, use a 
    second consecutive single quote. For example:

        'don''t'

    The output of this command is:

        don't


    To force Windows PowerShell to interpret a double quotation mark 
    literally, use a backtick character. This prevents Windows PowerShell
    from interpreting the quotation mark as a string delimiter. For example:

        "Use a quotation mark (`") to begin a string."

    Because the contents of single-quoted strings are 
    interpreted literally, you cannot use the backtick character to 
    force a literal character interpretation in a single-quoted string.

    For example, the following command generates an error because Windows 
    PowerShell does not recognize the escape character. Instead, it 
    interprets the second quotation mark as the end of the string.

        PS C:\> 'Use a quotation mark (`') to begin a string.'
        Unexpected token ')' in expression or statement.
        At line:1 char:27
        + 'Use a quotation mark (`') <<<<  to begin a string.'

 HERE-STRINGS
    The quotation rules for here-strings are slightly different.

    A here-string is a single-quoted or double-quoted string in 
    which quotation marks are interpreted literally. A here-string can 
    span multiple lines. All the lines in a here-string are interpreted
    as strings even though they are not enclosed in quotation marks.

    Like regular strings, variables are replaced by their values in 
    double-quoted here-strings. In single-quoted here-strings, variables
    are not replaced by their values.

    You can use here-strings for any text, but they are particularly
    useful for the following kinds of text:
    
    -- Text that contains literal quotation marks
    -- Multiple lines of text, such as the text in an HTML or XML document
    -- The Help text for a script or function

    A here-string can have either of the following formats, where <Enter> 
    represents the linefeed or newline hidden character that is added when
    you press the ENTER key.

     Double-quotes:
        @"<Enter>
        <string> [string] ...<Enter>
        "@

    Single-quotes:
        @'<Enter>
        <string> [string] ...<Enter>
        '@

    In either format, the closing quotation mark must be the first character 
    in the line. 

    A here-string contains all the text between the two hidden characters.
    In the here-string, all quotation marks are interpreted literally.
    For example:

        @"
        For help, type "get-help"
        "@

   The output of this command is:

        For help, type "get-help"

    Using a here-string can simplify using a string in a command. For 
    example:

        @"
        Use a quotation mark (') to begin a string.
        "@
    
    The output of this command is:

        Use a quotation mark (') to begin a string.

    In single-quoted here-strings, variables are interpreted literally and 
    reproduced exactly. For example:

        @'
        The $profile variable contains the path
        of your Windows PowerShell profile.
        '@

    The output of this command is:

        The $profile variable contains the path
        of your Windows PowerShell profile.


    In double-quoted here-strings, variables are replaced by their values. 
    For example:

        @" 
        Even if you have not created a profile,
        the path of the profile file is:
        $profile.
        "@
    
    The output of this command is:

        Even if you have not created a profile,
        the path of the profile file is:
        C:\Users\User01\Documents\WindowsPowerShell\Microsoft.PowerShell_profile.ps1.

    Here-strings are typically used to assign multiple lines to
    a variable. For example, the following here-string assigns a
    page of XML to the $page variable.

        $page = [XML] @"
        <command:command xmlns:maml="http://schemas.microsoft.com/maml/2004/10"
        xmlns:command="http://schemas.microsoft.com/maml/dev/command/2004/10" 
        xmlns:dev="http://schemas.microsoft.com/maml/dev/2004/10">
        <command:details>
                <command:name>
                       Format-Table
                </command:name>
                <maml:description>
                    <maml:para>Formats the output as a table.</maml:para>
                </maml:description>
                <command:verb>format</command:verb>
                <command:noun>table</command:noun>
                <dev:version></dev:version>
        </command:details>
        ...
        </command:command>
        "@


    Here-strings are also a convenient format for input to the 
    ConvertFrom-StringData cmdlet, which converts here-strings to hash 
    tables. For more information, see ConvertFrom-StringData.


KEYWORDS
    about_Here-Strings
    about_Quotes
    about_Quotation_Marks

SEE ALSO
    about_Escape_Characters
    ConvertFrom-StringData












