TOPIC
    about_Remote_FAQ

SHORT DESCRIPTION
    Contains questions and answers about running remote commands
    in Windows PowerShell.


LONG DESCRIPTION
   When you work remotely, you type commands in Windows PowerShell on one
   computer (known as the "local computer"), but the commands run on another
   computer (known as the "remote computer"). The experience of working 
   remotely should be as much like working directly at the remote computer
   as possible.

    Note: To use Windows PowerShell remoting, the remote computer
          must be configured for remoting. For more information, see
          about_Remote_Requirements. 
          

 MUST BOTH COMPUTERS HAVE WINDOWS POWERSHELL INSTALLED?

   Yes. To work remotely, the local and remote computers must have
   Windows PowerShell, the Microsoft .NET Framework, and the Web
   Services for Management (WS-Management) protocol. Any files and
   other resources that are needed to execute a particular command 
   must be on the remote computer.

   Computers running Windows PowerShell 3.0 and computers running 
   Windows PowerShell 2.0 can connect to each other remotely and run
   remote commands. However, some features, such as the ability to
   disconnect from a session and reconnect to it, work only when both
   computers are running Windows PowerShell 3.0.

   You must have permission to connect to the remote computer, permission
   to run Windows PowerShell, and permission to access data stores (such as
   files and folders), and the registry on the remote computer.

   For more information, see about_Remote_Requirements.   


 HOW DOES REMOTING WORK?

   When you submit a remote command, the command is transmitted across
   the network to the Windows PowerShell engine on the remote computer, 
   and it runs in the Windows PowerShell client on the remote computer.
   The command results are sent back to the local computer and appear in 
   the Windows PowerShell session on the local computer.

   To transmit the commands and receive the output, Windows PowerShell uses 
   the WS-Management protocol. For information about the WS-Management
   protocol, see "WS-Management Protocol" in the MSDN (Microsoft Developer
   Network) library at http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=144634.   

   Beginning in Windows PowerShell 3.0, remote sessions are stored on 
   the remote computer. This enables you to disconnect from the session 
   and reconnect from a different session or a different computer without
   interrupting the commands or losing state.

 IS WINDOWS POWERSHELL REMOTING SECURE?

    When you connect to a remote computer, the system uses the user
    name and password credentials on the local computer or the credentials
    that you supply in the command to log you in to the remote computer. 
    The credentials and the rest of the transmission are encrypted. 

    To add additional protection, you can configure the remote computer
    to use Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) instead of HTTP to listen for
    Windows Remote Management (WinRM) requests. Then, users can use 
    the UseSSL parameters of the Invoke-Command, New-PSSession, and
    Enter-PSSession cmdlets when establishing a connection. This option
    uses the more secure HTTPS channel instead of HTTP.


 DO ALL REMOTE COMMANDS REQUIRE WINDOWS POWERSHELL REMOTING?

   No. Several cmdlets have a ComputerName parameter that lets
   you get objects from the remote computer. 

   These cmdlets do not use Windows PowerShell remoting. So, you
   can use them on any computer that is running Windows PowerShell,
   even if the computer is not configured for Windows PowerShell
   remoting or if the computer does not meet the requirements for
   Windows PowerShell remoting.

   These cmdlets include the following cmdlets:

       Get-Process
       Get-Service
       Get-WinEvent
       Get-EventLog
       Get-WmiObject
       Test-Connection


   To find all the cmdlets with a ComputerName parameter, type:

        Get-Help * -Parameter ComputerName
        or 
        Get-Command -ParameterName ComputerName   

   To determine whether the ComputerName parameter of a particular cmdlet
   requires Windows PowerShell remoting, see the parameter description. To
   display the parameter description, type:

Get-Help <cmdlet-name> -Parameter ComputerName

   For example:

        Get-Help Get-Process -Parameter Computername

   For all other commands, use the Invoke-Command cmdlet.


 HOW DO I RUN A COMMAND ON A REMOTE COMPUTER?

   To run a command on a remote computer, use the Invoke-Command cmdlet.

   Enclose your command in braces ( {} ) to make it a script block. Use 
   the ScriptBlock parameter of Invoke-Command to specify the command.

   You can use the ComputerName parameter of Invoke-Command to specify 
   a remote computer. Or, you can create a persistent connection to a remote
   computer (a session) and then use the Session parameter of Invoke-Command
   to run the command in the session. 


   For example, the following commands run a Get-Process command remotely.

      Invoke-Command -ComputerName Server01, Server02 -ScriptBlock {Get-Process}

        - OR -

      Invoke-Command -Session $s -ScriptBlock {Get-Process}

   To interrupt a remote command, type CTRL+C. The interruption request is 
   passed to the remote computer, where it terminates the remote command.

   For more information about remote commands, see about_Remote and the Help
   topics for the cmdlets that support remoting. 


 CAN I JUST "TELNET INTO" A REMOTE COMPUTER?

    You can use the Enter-PSSession cmdlet to start an interactive session 
    with a remote computer.

    At the Windows PowerShell prompt, type:

Enter-PSSession <ComputerName>

    The command prompt changes to show that you are connected to the remote
    computer.

        <ComputerName>\C:> 

    Now, the commands that you type run on the remote computer just as 
    though you typed them directly on the remote computer.

    To end the interactive session, type:

        Exit-PSSession

    An interactive session is a persistent session that uses the WS-Management
    protocol. It is not the same as using Telnet, but it provides a similar 
    experience.

    For more information, see Enter-PSSession.


 CAN I CREATE A PERSISTENT CONNECTION? 

    Yes. You can run remote commands by specifying the name of the 
    remote computer, its NetBIOS name, or its IP address. Or, you can run
    remote commands by specifying a Windows PowerShell session (PSSession) 
    that is connected to the remote computer.
    
    When you use the ComputerName parameter of Invoke-Command or 
    Enter-PSSession, Windows PowerShell establishes a temporary
    connection. Windows PowerShell uses the connection to run only the current
    command, and then it closes the connection. This is a very efficient 
    method for running a single command or several unrelated commands, even
    on many remote computers.

    When you use the New-PSSession cmdlet to create a PSSession, Windows
    PowerShell establishes a persistent connection for the PSSession. Then, 
    you can run multiple commands in the PSSession, including commands that
    share data.

    Typically, you create a PSSession to run a series of related commands
    that share data. Otherwise, the temporary connection created by the 
    ComputerName parameter is sufficient for most commands. 

    For more information about sessions, see about_PSSessions.


 CAN I RUN COMMANDS ON MORE THAN ONE COMPUTER AT A TIME?

   Yes. The ComputerName parameter of the Invoke-Command cmdlet accepts
   multiple computer names, and the Session parameter accepts
   multiple PSSessions. 

   When you run an Invoke-Command command, Windows PowerShell runs the
   commands on all of the specified computers or in all of the specified
   PSSessions.

   Windows PowerShell can manage hundreds of concurrent remote connections. 
   However, the number of remote commands that you can send might be limited
   by the resources of your computer and its capacity to establish and
   maintain multiple network connections. 

   For more information, see the example in the Invoke-Command Help 
   topic.


 WHERE ARE MY PROFILES?

    Windows PowerShell profiles are not run automatically in remote sessions,
    so the commands that the profile adds are not present in the session. In
    addition, the $profile automatic variable is not populated in remote
    sessions.    

    To run a profile in a session, use the Invoke-Command cmdlet.

    For example, the following command runs the CurrentUserCurrentHost profile
    from the local computer in the session in $s. 

        Invoke-Command -Session $s -FilePath $profile


    The following command runs the CurrentUserCurrentHost profile from 
    the remote computer in the session in $s. Because the $profile variable 
    is not populated, the command uses the explicit path to the profile.

        Invoke-Command -Session $s {. "$home\Documents\WindowsPowerShell\Microsoft.PowerShell_profile.ps1"}


    After running this command, the commands that the profile adds to the session
    are available in $s.

    You can also use a startup script in a session configuration to run a
    profile in every remote session that uses the session configuration.

    For more information about Windows PowerShell profiles,
    see about_Profiles. For more information about session configurations,
    see Register-PSSessionConfiguration.



 HOW DOES THROTTLING WORK ON REMOTE COMMANDS?

   To help you manage the resources on your local computer, Windows
   PowerShell includes a per-command throttling feature that lets you
   limit the number of concurrent remote connections that are established
   for each command. 

   The default is 32 concurrent connections, but you can use the
   ThrottleLimit parameters of the cmdlets to set a custom throttle limit
   for particular commands. 

   When you use the throttling feature, remember that it is applied to each
   command, not to the entire session or to the computer. If you are running
   commands concurrently in several sessions or PSSessions, the number of 
   concurrent connections is the sum of the concurrent connections in all 
   the sessions.

   To find cmdlets with a ThrottleLimit parameter, type:

Get-Help * -Parameter ThrottleLimit
      -or-
      Get-Command -ParameterName ThrottleLimit






















 IS THE OUTPUT OF REMOTE COMMANDS DIFFERENT FROM LOCAL OUTPUT?
   
   When you use Windows PowerShell locally, you send and receive "live" .NET
   Framework objects; "live" objects are objects that are associated with 
   actual programs or system components. When you invoke the methods or change
   the properties of live objects, the changes affect the actual program or 
   component. And, when the properties of a program or component change, 
   the properties of the object that represent them also change. 

   However, because most live objects cannot be transmitted over the network, 
   Windows PowerShell "serializes" most of the objects sent in remote commands,
   that is, it converts each object into a series of XML (Constraint Language
   in XML [CLiXML]) data elements for transmission. 

   When Windows PowerShell receives a serialized object, it converts
   the XML into a deserialized object type. The deserialized object
   is an accurate record of the properties of the program or component at
   a previous time, but it is no longer "live", that is, it
   is no longer directly associated with the component. And, the methods are
   removed because they are no longer effective.

   Typically, you can use deserialized objects just as you would use live
   objects, but you must be aware of their limitations. Also, the objects
   that are returned by the Invoke-Command cmdlet have additional properties
   that help you to determine the origin of the command. 

   Some object types, such as DirectoryInfo objects and GUIDs, are converted
   back into live objects when they are received. These objects do not need
   any special handling or formatting.   

   For information about interpreting and formatting remote output, see
   about_Remote_Output.


 CAN I RUN BACKGROUND JOBS REMOTELY?

   Yes. A Windows PowerShell background job is a Windows PowerShell
   command that runs asynchronously without interacting with the session. When
   you start a background job, the command prompt returns immediately, and you
   can continue to work in the session while the job runs even if it runs for
   an extended period of time.
   
   You can start a background job even while other commands are running because
   background jobs always run asynchronously in a temporary session.

   You can run background jobs on a local or remote computer. By default, a
   background job runs on the local computer. However, you can use the AsJob
   parameter of the Invoke-Command cmdlet to run any remote command as a
   background job. And, you can use Invoke-Command to run a Start-Job
   command remotely.   

   For more information about background jobs in Windows PowerShell,
   see about_Jobs and about_Remote_Jobs.       


 CAN I RUN WINDOWS PROGRAMS ON A REMOTE COMPUTER?
 
    You can use Windows PowerShell remote commands to run Windows-based
    programs on remote computers. For example, you can run Shutdown.exe 
    or Ipconfig on a remote computer. 

    However, you cannot use Windows PowerShell commands to open the user 
    interface for any program on a remote computer.  

    When you start a Windows program on a remote computer, the command is
    not completed, and the Windows PowerShell command prompt does not return,
    until the program is finished or until you press CTRL+C to interrupt the
    command. For example, if you run the IpConfig program on a remote computer,
    the command prompt does not return until IpConfig is completed.
 
    If you use remote commands to start a program that has a user interface,
    the program process starts, but the user interface does not appear. The
    Windows PowerShell command is not completed, and the command prompt does
    not return until you stop the program process or until you press CTRL+C,
    which interrupts the command and stops the process.
 
    For example, if you use a Windows PowerShell command to run Notepad on a
    remote computer, the Notepad process starts on the remote computer, but
    the Notepad user interface does not appear. To interrupt the command and
    restore the command prompt, press CTRL+C.
 

 CAN I LIMIT THE COMMANDS THAT USERS CAN RUN REMOTELY ON MY COMPUTER?

    Yes. Every remote session must use one of the session configurations
    on the remote computer. You can manage the session configurations on
    your computer (and the permissions to those session configurations)
    to determine who can run commands remotely on your computer and which
    commands they can run.

    A session configuration configures the environment for the session.
    You can define the configuration by using an assembly that implements
    a new configuration class or by using a script that runs in the session.
    The configuration can determine the commands that are available in the
    session. And, the configuration can include settings that protect the
    computer, such as settings that limit the amount of data that the session
    can receive remotely in a single object or command. You can also specify
    a security descriptor that determines the permissions that are required 
    to use the configuration.

    The Enable-PSRemoting cmdlet creates the default session configurations
    on your computer: Microsoft.PowerShell, Microsoft.PowerShell.Workflow,
    and Microsoft.PowerShell32 (64-bit operating systems only). 
    Enable-PSRemoting sets the security descriptor for the configuration to
    allow only members of the Administrators group on your computer to use them.
 
    You can use the session configuration cmdlets to edit the default 
    session configurations, to create new session configurations, and to change
    the security descriptors of all the session configurations.

    Beginning in Windows PowerShell 3.0, the New-SessionConfigurationFile 
    cmdlet lets you create custom session configurations by using a text 
    file. The file includes options for setting the language mode and for
    specifying the cmdlets and modules that are available in sessions that
    use the session configuration.

    When users use the Invoke-Command, New-PSSession, or Enter-PSSession
    cmdlets, they can use the ConfigurationName parameter to indicate the
    session configuration that is used for the session. And, they can change
    the default configuration that their sessions use by changing the value
    of the $PSSessionConfigurationName preference variable in the session. 

    For more information about session configurations, see the Help for 
    the session configuration cmdlets. To find the session configuration
    cmdlets, type:

Get-Command *PSSessionConfiguration

   

 WHAT ARE FAN-IN AND FAN OUT CONFIGURATIONS?

   The most common Windows PowerShell remoting scenario involving
   multiple computers is the one-to-many configuration, in which one
   local computer (the administrator's computer) runs Windows PowerShell
   commands on numerous remote computers. This is known as the
   "fan-out" scenario. 

   However, in some enterprises, the configuration is many-to-one, where
   many client computers connect to a single remote computer that is
   running Windows PowerShell, such as a file server or a kiosk.
   This is known as the "fan-in" configuration.

   Windows PowerShell remoting supports both fan-out and fan-in 
   configurations. 

   For the fan-out configuration, Windows PowerShell uses the Web Services for
   Management (WS-Management) protocol and the WinRM service that supports the
   Microsoft implementation of WS-Management. When a local computer connects to
   a remote computer, WS-Management establishes a connection and uses a plug-in
   for Windows PowerShell to start the Windows PowerShell host process
   (Wsmprovhost.exe) on the remote computer. The user can specify an alternate
   port, an alternate session configuration, and other features to customize
   the remote connection.   

   To support the "fan-in" configuration, Windows PowerShell uses Internet
   Information Services (IIS) to host WS-Management, to load the Windows
   PowerShell plug-in, and to start Windows PowerShell. In this scenario,
   instead of starting each Windows PowerShell session in a separate process,
   all Windows PowerShell sessions run in the same host process. 

   IIS hosting and fan-in remote management is not supported in Windows XP or
   in Windows Server 2003.

   In a fan-in configuration, the user can specify a connection URI and an
   HTTP endpoint, including the transport, computer name, port, and application
   name. IIS forwards all the requests with a specified application name to the
   application. The default is WS-Management, which can host Windows 
   PowerShell.

   You can also specify an authentication mechanism and prohibit or allow
   redirection from HTTP and HTTPS endpoints. 
      

 CAN I TEST REMOTING ON A SINGLE COMPUTER (NOT IN A DOMAIN)?

    Yes. Windows PowerShell remoting is available even when the local
    computer is not in a domain. You can use the remoting features to
    connect to sessions and to create sessions on the same computer. The 
    features work the same as they do when you connect to a remote computer.

    To run remote commands on a computer in a workgroup, change the
    following Windows settings on the computer.

    Caution: These settings affect all users on the system and they can
             make the system more vulnerable to a malicious attack. Use
             caution when making these changes.


    --  Windows XP with SP2: 

        Use Local Security Settings (Secpol.msc) to change the setting of the
        "Network Access: Sharing and security model for local accounts" policy
        in Security Settings\Local Policies\Security Options to "Classic".


    --  Windows Vista, Windows 7, Windows 8: 

        Create the following registry entry, and then set its value to 1:
        LocalAccountTokenFilterPolicy in 
        HKLM\SOFTWARE\Microsoft\Windows\CurrentVersion\Policies\System

        You can use the following Windows PowerShell command to add this entry:

        New-ItemProperty `
        –Path HKLM:\SOFTWARE\Microsoft\Windows\CurrentVersion\Policies\System `
        –Name LocalAccountTokenFilterPolicy –propertyType DWord –Value 1

    --  Windows Server 2003, Windows Server 2008, Windows Server 8: 

        No changes are needed because the default setting of the 
        "Network Access: Sharing and security model for local accounts" policy
        is "Classic". Verify the setting in case it has changed.


 CAN I RUN REMOTE COMMANDS ON A COMPUTER IN ANOTHER DOMAIN?

    Yes. Typically, the commands run without error, although you might need
    to use the Credential parameter of the Invoke-Command, New-PSSession,
    or Enter-PSSession cmdlets to provide the credentials of a member of the 
    Administrators group on the remote computer. This is sometimes required 
    even when the current user is a member of the Administrators group on the
    local and remote computers. 

    However, if the remote computer is not in a domain that the local computer
    trusts, the remote computer might not be able to authenticate the user's
    credentials.

    To enable authentication, use the following command to add the remote 
    computer to the list of trusted hosts for the local computer in WinRM.
    Type the command at the Windows PowerShell prompt.

        Set-Item WSMan:\localhost\Client\TrustedHosts -Value <Remote-computer-name>

    For example, to add the Server01 computer to the list of trusted hosts
    on the local computer, type the following command at the Windows 
    PowerShell prompt:

        Set-Item WSMan:\localhost\Client\TrustedHosts -Value Server01


SEE ALSO
    about_Remote
    about_Profiles
    about_PSSessions
    about_Remote_Jobs
    about_Remote_Variables
    Invoke-Command
    New-PSSession












