about_Join
TOPIC
    about_join

SHORT DESCRIPTION
    Describes how the join operator (-join) combines multiple strings into a 
    single string.


LONG DESCRIPTION
    The join operator concatenates a set of strings into a single string. The
    strings are appended to the resulting string in the order that they appear
    in the command. 


  Syntax
      The following diagram shows the syntax for the join operator.

         -Join <String[]>
        <String[]> -Join <Delimiter>


  Parameters
      String[]
          Specifies one or more strings to be joined.


      Delimiter
          Specifies one or more characters placed between the concatenated strings.
          The default is no delimiter ("").


  Remarks
      The unary join operator (-join <string[]>) has higher precedence than
      a comma. As a result, if you submit a comma-separated list of strings to
      the unary join operator, only the first string (before the first comma) 
      is submitted to the join operator.


      To use the unary join operator, enclose the strings in parentheses, or
      store the strings in a variable, and then submit the variable to join.


      For example:

          -join "a", "b", "c"
          a
          b
          c

          -join ("a", "b", "c")
          abc


          $z = "a", "b", "c"
          -join $z
          abc


  Examples
      The following statement joins three strings:


          -join ("Windows", "PowerShell", "2.0")
          WindowsPowerShell2.0


      The following statement joins three strings delimited by a space:


          "Windows", "PowerShell", "2.0" -join " "
          Windows PowerShell 2.0


      The following statements use a multiple-character delimiter to join 
      three strings:


          $a = "WIND", "SP", "ERSHELL" 
          $a -join "OW"
          WINDOWSPOWERSHELL


      The following statement joins the lines in a here-string into
      a single string. Because a here-string is one string, the lines in the
      here-string must be split before they can be joined. You can use this 
      method to rejoin the strings in an XML file that has been saved in a 
      here-string:


          $a = @'
          a
          b
          c
          '@

          (-split $a) -join " "
          a b c


SEE ALSO
    about_Operators
    about_Comparison_Operators
    about_Split












