about_Switch
TOPIC
    about_Switch

SHORT DESCRIPTION
    Explains how to use a switch to handle multiple If statements.

LONG DESCRIPTION
    To check a condition in a script or function, use an If statement. 
    The If can check many types of conditions, including the value of 
    variables and the properties of objects.

    To check multiple conditions, use a Switch statement. The Switch
    statement is equivalent to a series of If statements, but it is 
    simpler. The Switch statement lists each condition and an optional
    action. If a condition obtains, the action is performed.

    A basic Switch statement has the following format:
        
        Switch (<test-value>)
        {
            <condition> {<action>}
            <condition> {<action>}
       }

    For example, the following Switch statement compares the test 
    value, 3, to each of the conditions. When the test value matches
    the condition, the action is performed.

        PS> switch (3) 
         {
            1 {"It is one."}
            2 {"It is two."}
            3 {"It is three."}
            4 {"It is four."}
         } 
        It is three.

    In this simple example, the value is compared to each condition
    in the list, even though there is a match for the value 3. The 
    following Switch statement has two conditions for a value of 3.
    It demonstrates that, by default, all conditions are tested.

        PS> switch (3) 
         {
            1 {"It is one."}
            2 {"It is two."}
            3 {"It is three."}
            4 {"It is four."}
            3 {"Three again."}
         } 
        It is three.
        Three again.

    To direct the Switch to stop comparing after a match, use the 
    Break statement. The Break statement terminates the Switch
    statement. 

        PS> switch (3) 
         {
            1 {"It is one."}
            2 {"It is two."}
            3 {"It is three."; Break}
            4 {"It is four."}
            3 {"Three again."}
         } 
        It is three.

    If the test value is a collection, such as an array, each 
    item in the collection is evaluated in the order in which it
    appears. The following examples evaluates 4 and then 2.

         PS> switch (4, 2) 
         {
            1 {"It is one." }
            2 {"It is two." }
            3 {"It is three." }
            4 {"It is four." }
            3 {"Three again."}
         } 
        It is four.
        It is two.

    Any Break statements apply to the collection, not to 
    each value, as shown in the following example. The
    Switch statement is terminated by the Break statement
    in the condition of value 4.

         PS> switch (4, 2) 
         {
            1 {"It is one."; Break}
            2 {"It is two." ; Break }
            3 {"It is three." ; Break }
            4 {"It is four." ; Break }
            3 {"Three again."}
         } 
        It is four.

 SYNTAX
    The complete Switch statement syntax is as follows:

        switch [-regex|-wildcard|-exact][-casesensitive] (<value>)
    
    or

        switch [-regex|-wildcard|-exact][-casesensitive] -file filename

    followed by

        { 
            "string"|number|variable|{ expression } { statementlist }
            default { statementlist } 
        }

    
    If no parameters are used, Switch performs a case-insensitive 
    exact match for the value. If the value is a collection, each
    element is evaluated in the order in which it appears.   

    The Switch statement must include at least one condition statement. 

    The Default clause is triggered when the value does not match
    any of the conditions. It is equivalent to an Else clause in 
    an If statement. Only one Default clause is permitted in each 
    Switch statement.

    Switch has the following parameters:

        Regex      Performs regular expression matching of the 
                        value to the condition. If you use Regex,
                        Wildcard and Exact are ignored. Also, if the 
                        match clause is not a string, this parameter 
                        is ignored.

                           Example:
                           PS> switch ("fourteen") 
                               {
                                   1 {"It is one."; Break}
                                   2 {"It is two."; Break}
                                   3 {"It is three."; Break}
                                   4 {"It is four."; Break}
                                   3 {"Three again."; Break}
                                   "fo*" {"That's too many."}
                               } 

                           PS> switch -Regex ("fourteen") 
                               {
                                   1 {"It is one."; Break}
                                   2 {"It is two."; Break}
                                   3 {"It is three."; Break}
                                   4 {"It is four."; Break}
                                   3 {"Three again."; Break}
                                   "fo*" {"That's too many."}
                               }
                        That's too many.

        Wildcard      Indicates that the condition is a wildcard string. 
                        If you use Wildcard, Regex and Exact are ignored. 
                        Also, if the match clause is not a string, this 
                        parameter is ignored.

        Exact      Indicates that the match clause, if it is a string, 
                        must match exactly. If you use Exact, Regex and 
                        Wildcard and Exact are ignored. Also, if the match 
                        clause is not a string, this parameter is ignored.

        CaseSensitivePerforms a case-sensitive match. If the match 
                        clause is not a string, this parameter is ignored.

        File      Takes input from a file rather than a value 
                        statement. If multiple File parameters are 
                        included, only the last one is used. Each line of the 
                        file is read and evaluated by the Switch statement.

    Multiple instances of Regex, Wildcard, or Exact are permitted. However, only 
    the last parameter used is effective.

    If the value matches multiple conditions, the action for each
    condition is executed. To change this behavior, use the Break 
    or Continue keywords.

    The Break keyword stops processing and exits the Switch statement.  

    The Continue keyword continues processing the current value and
    any subsequent values.

    If the condition is an expression or a script block, it is
    evaluated just before it is compared to the value. The value is 
    assigned to the $_ automatic variable and is available in the 
    expression. The match succeeds if the expression is true or 
    matches the value. The expression is evaluated in its own scope.

    The "Default" keyword specifies a condition that is evaluated
    only when no other conditions match the value. 

    The action for each condition is independent of the actions in
    other conditions. The closing brace ( } ) in the action is an 
    explicit break. 


SEE ALSO
    about_Break
    about_Continue
    about_If
    about_Script_Blocks












