TOPIC
    about_Remote_Requirements

SHORT DESCRIPTION
    Describes the system requirements and configuration requirements for 
    running remote commands in Windows PowerShell.

LONG DESCRIPTION
    This topic describes the system requirements, user requirements, and
    resource requirements for establishing remote connections and running
    remote commands in Windows PowerShell. It also provides instructions for
    configuring remote operations.

    Note: Many cmdlets (including the Get-Service, Get-Process, Get-WMIObject,
          Get-EventLog, and Get-WinEvent cmdlets) get objects from remote
          computers by using Microsoft .NET Framework methods to retrieve the
          objects. They do not use the Windows PowerShell remoting 
          infrastructure. The requirements in this document do not apply to 
          these cmdlets.

          To find the cmdlets that have a ComputerName parameter but do not use
          Windows PowerShell remoting, read the description of the ComputerName
          parameter of the cmdlets.
          

 SYSTEM REQUIREMENTS

    To run remote sessions on Windows PowerShell 3.0, the local and remote computers
    must have the following:

        --  Windows PowerShell 3.0 or later
        --  The Microsoft .NET Framework 4.0 or later
        --  Windows Remote Management 3.0

    To run remote sessions on Windows PowerShell 2.0, the local and remote computers
    must have the following:

        --  Windows PowerShell 2.0 or later
        --  The Microsoft .NET Framework 2.0 or later
        --  Windows Remote Management 2.0

    You can create remote sessions between computers running Windows PowerShell 2.0
    and Windows PowerShell 3.0. However, features that run only on Windows     
    PowerShell 3.0, such as the ability to disconnect and reconnect to sessions, are
    available only when both computers are running Windows PowerShell 3.0.

    To find the version number of an installed version of Windows PowerShell,
    use the $PSVersionTable automatic variable. 

    Windows Remote Management (WinRM) 3.0 and Microsoft .NET Framework 4.0 are included
    in Windows 8 and Windows Server 8. WinRM 3.0 is included in Windows Management
    Framework 3.0 for downlevel systems. If the computer does not have the required
    version of WinRM or the Microsoft .NET Framework, the installation fails.



 USER PERMISSIONS
 
    To create remote sessions and run remote commands, by default, the current 
    user must be a member of the Administrators group on the remote computer or 
    provide the credentials of an administrator. Otherwise, the command fails.

    The permissions required to create sessions and run commands on a remote
    computer (or in a remote session on the local computer) are established by
    the session configuration (also known as an "endpoint") on the remote 
    computer to which the  session connects. Specifically, the security
    descriptor on the session configuration determines who has access to the
    session configuration and who can use it to connect. 

    The security descriptors on the default session configurations, 
    Microsoft.PowerShell, Microsoft.PowerShell32, and 
    Microsoft.PowerShell.Workflow, allow access only to members of the
    Administrators group. 

    If the current user doesn't have permission to use the session configuration,
    the command to run a command (which uses a temporary session) or create 
    a persistent session on the remote computer fails. The user can use the
    ConfigurationName parameter of cmdlets that create sessions to select a
    different session configuration, if one is available.

    Members of the Administrators group on a computer can determine who has 
    permission to connect to the computer remotely by changing the security
    descriptors on the default session configurations and by creating new
    session configurations with different security descriptors.

    For more informations about session configurations, see 
    about_Session_Configurations (http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkID=145152).


  WINDOWS NETWORK LOCATIONS
    Beginning in Windows PowerShell 3.0, the Enable-PSRemoting cmdlet can enable
    remoting on client and server versions of Windows on private, domain, and
    public networks.  

    On server versions of Windows with private and domain networks, the
    Enable-PSRemoting cmdlet creates  firewall rules that allow unrestricted 
    remote access. It also creates a firewall rule for public networks that
    allows remote  access only from computers in the same local subnet. This
    local subnet firewall rule is enabled by default on server versions of
    Windows on public networks, but Enable-PSRemoting reapplies the rule in
    case it was changed or deleted.

    On client versions of Windows with private and domain networks, by
    default, the Enable-PSRemoting cmdlet creates firewall rules that 
    allow unrestricted remote access.

    To enable remoting on client versions of Windows with public networks, 
    use the SkipNetworkProfileCheck parameter of the Enable-PSRemoting cmdlet.
    It creates a firewall rule that that allows remote access only from 
    computers in the same local subnet.

    To remove the local subnet restriction on public networks and allow remote
    access from all locations on client and server versions of Windows, use
    the Set-NetFirewallRule cmdlet in the NetSecurity module. Run the following
    command:

        Set-NetFirewallRule –Name "WINRM-HTTP-In-TCP-PUBLIC" –RemoteAddress Any   


    In Windows PowerShell 2.0, on server versions of Windows, Enable-PSRemoting 
    creates firewall rules that permit remote access on all networks.

    In Windows PowerShell 2.0, on client versions of Windows, Enable-PSRemoting
    creates firewall rules only on private and domain networks. If the network
    location is public, Enable-PSRemoting fails.
.


 RUN AS ADMINISTRATOR

    Administrator privileges are required for the following remoting
    operations:

        -- Establishing a remote connection to the local computer. This is
           commonly known as a "loopback" scenario. 
      
        -- Managing session configurations on the local computer.

        -- Viewing and changing WS-Management settings on the local computer.
           These are the settings in the LocalHost node of the WSMAN: drive.


    To perform these tasks, you must start Windows PowerShell with the "Run
    as administrator" option even if you are a member of the Administrators
    group on the local computer.

    In Windows 7 and in Windows Server 2008 R2, to start Windows PowerShell
    with the "Run as administrator" option:

        1. Click Start, click All Programs, click Accessories, and then click
           the Windows PowerShell folder.

        2. Right-click Windows PowerShell, and then click 
           "Run as administrator".

    To start Windows PowerShell with the "Run as administrator" option: 

        1. Click Start, click All Programs, and then click the Windows 
           PowerShell folder.

        2. Right-click Windows PowerShell, and then click 
           "Run as administrator".
    
    The "Run as administrator" option is also available in other Windows 
    Explorer entries for Windows PowerShell, including shortcuts. Just 
    right-click the item, and then click "Run as administrator".

    When you start Windows PowerShell from another program such as Cmd.exe, use
    the "Run as administrator" option to start the program.         


 HOW TO CONFIGURE YOUR COMPUTER FOR REMOTING   

    Computers running all supported versions of Windows can establish remote
    connections to and run remote commands in Windows PowerShell without any
    configuration. However, to receive connections, and allow users to create
    local and remote user-managed Windows PowerShell sessions ("PSSessions")
    and run commands on the local computer, you must enable Windows PowerShell
    remoting on the computer.

    Windows Server 8 is enabled for Windows PowerShell remoting by default.
    If the settings are changed, you can restore the default settings by 
    by running the Enable-PSRemoting cmdlet.

    On all other supported versions of Windows, you need to run the 
    Enable-PSRemoting cmdlet to enable Windows PowerShell remoting.

    The remoting features of Windows PowerShell are supported by the WinRM
    service, which is the Microsoft implementation of the Web Services for
    Management (WS-Management) protocol. When you enable Windows PowerShell 
    remoting, you change the default configuration of WS-Management and add
    system configuration that allow users to connect to WS-Management. 

    To configure Windows PowerShell to receive remote commands: 

      1. Start Windows PowerShell with the "Run as administrator"
         option.

2. At the command prompt, type:
   Enable-PSRemoting

    To verify that remoting is configured correctly, run a test command such as
    the following command, which creates a remote session on the local 
    computer.

          New-PSSession


    If remoting is configured correctly, the command will create a session on 
    the local computer and return an object that represents the session. The 
    output should resemble the following sample output:

          C:\PS> new-pssession

          Id Name        ComputerName    State    ConfigurationName
          -- ----        ------------    -----    -----
          1  Session1    localhost       Opened   Microsoft.PowerShell


    If the command fails, for assistance, see about_Remote_Troubleshooting.


 UNDERSTAND POLICIES

    When you work remotely, you use two instances of Windows PowerShell, one 
    on the local computer and one on the remote computer. As a result, your 
    work is affected by the Windows policies and the Windows PowerShell 
    policies on the local and remote computers.

    In general, before you connect and as you are establishing the connection,
    the policies on the local computer are in effect. When you are using the 
    connection, the policies on the remote computer are in effect.


SEE ALSO
    about_Remote
    about_Remote_Variables
    about_PSSessions
    Invoke-Command
    Enter-PSSession
    New-PSSession












